Welcome back. In the previous step we created an Angular application using Angular CLI.
And we have launched it up, and we saw a plain UI coming up. In the step, what we'll do is we'll import
the project into our favorite IDE, which is a visual studio code. Let's get started now.
I'm sure you would have the visual studio code installed.
We had it as part of our installation section when you launch up your code.
This is the screen you would see. This is the welcome screen and you would be able to see a few help
documentation. You can see the recent projects I had worked on a lot, to make sure that this course is perfect and
you can see other stuff about how you can customize and learn about the visual studio code. If you
have some time,
I would recommend you to spend some time exploring the IDE.
One of the things that I have done is I'm using a specific visual studio theme. So if you go to code ->
preferences... if you're on Windows it's file preferences.
You can change the color theme.
What I've done is I'm using a light Visual Studio Theme. I like very light so that it appears clear on
the video, and you can also see this very well on your mobiles.
But if you like dark then you can leave it...the default does this.
Now let's get to the first task of this step, which is to import the project in.
The thing is, in code, importing a project is very easy.
Either you can say open for later, or an even more lazy way of doing it.
Just go to the folder where
we have the project, in todo the project ,and just drag and drop it in.
And that's that the project would launch up. When the project launches up, you would see the Explorer
view.
So this view which we are seeing in here, is the Explorer view. You can toggle it, and toggle it down by  clicking
this icon which just is in here.
Let's open up the files which is present in here: README.md. README.md contain certain
amount of documentation about the project that we have created.
So it says it was generated using AngularCLI.
version 7.0.3.
It says you can do ng serve.
That's what we're doing right now.
And you can use this, you are ready to launch it.
And that's what we did.
Well yes, well there's lot of documentation in here.
You might want to check that out if you want to see this in full screen.
So README is now taking part of the screen, and the Explorer is taking some of the part of the screen.
So you can tell by clicking this, or the other option is to use control-B, or command-B.
So control-B /  command-B.
So if you're on Mac it's command-B, if you are on Windows or Linux it's going to be control-B. So use that and you
you'd be able to see the entire thing in full screen.
So this is something that would be using frequently.
So I just wanted to make sure that you are aware of that.
We'll explain more about your code as we go forward in this course.
I'll see you in the next step.