Welcome back. In the previous step, we're able to take data from the component view logic, the component
typescript code, and show it in the view in the template.
We were able to show in28minutes, when we refresh the page you'd see in28minutes as the user name. What
what we saw is when I typed in in28minutesExtended or changed, and clicked login, I was still seeing
in28minutes printed in the console. I was not able to get the value from the form element and tied
back to the business logic. That that's what we should be focusing on in this specific step.
Until now, we looked at 2 kinds of data.
First one uses interplolation.
The second one was event binding.
What we want to do now, is talk about the third kind which is a mix of both of these.
This is called "banana-in-a-box-approach".
So the syntax for this would look something like this.
And that's the reason why it's called "banana-in-a-box".
So think of it like you're putting a banana within a box.
That's basically the syntax
And there is a specific Angular feature we need to use to enable this.
This is called ngModel. Then what we are doing is we are trying to bing this value to a model element
and there is that model element present in username.
What we need to say is in ngModel = username.
I'm removing the value because we don't really need this anymore, because the ngModel would do binding
on both the sides.
It would take data from the login component, and tied down to the template and when data is changing
on the template, it would automatically update the value inside the component.
Let's save this and let's go to the browser.
There is a compilation error.
It says cannot bind in the model, because it's not really a known property of input.
So what we're trying to do is we're trying to make use of a feature called in ngModel.
Think of it like a class.
So this is a class from another module.
I'm trying to make use of it in here.
Which model does a component belong to? The login component where is it declared it's declared inside
the module.
So the logging component belongs to the app module.
This model really I would want to make use of a feature called ngModule.
What I would need to do, is I would need to import that module into the module.
I wanted to tell app module wants to make use of a specific module.
How can I do that? The way Ican do that by importing the forms module so that the ngModel is defined
as part of something called form module.
So you need to import form module into the component.
I'm now saying manually add the import, so I'll copy this one.
So I'll say import forms module, and it's defined in module called angular/forms.
So once you do this import, now you could go to the browser and wait for it to refresh.
You'd see that now in28 minutes, what the screen is shown.
And when I click login, it would print in28minutes, and it's right. When I change the data and print
login.
Interesting! we see the change to data!
So what is happening now, is this data is now having something called directional binding.
These are also called two way data binding.
We're able to take the data from the view logic of the logging component and right down to a template
to the HTML.
So we were able to show the default value as in28minutes.
Where is this, and when it is coming from? It's coming from the view logic from the component, and then
we changed it, and we change it and click login. What is happening?
This data is getting printed.
Where is it getting it from?
It's getting printed from user name.
And how did it get to the user name?
How was the user name element updated with the latest value?
It's because of this feature called data binding.
I'll recommend you to implement the data binding for password as an exercise.
I'll see you in the next step.