Welcome back. We left you with an exercise. We wanted to use data binding for the password field when you left.
It's very simple.
I can replace the values password with ngModel  = to... this.
It should be password and you want to replace with password.
You see that through the data binding is now working for password field as well.
If I go to the handleLogin and if you do console.log( this.password), it would open up the browser.
You would see that.
Now if I put in a login, it would also print the username and the password. If I enter the password
as dummy.
It's printing username and password. One of the important things that you need to remember
is this is not really a secure thing to do.
You would never want to print passwords out.
So what I would do is immediately remove this console.log() for password.
Let's quickly review some of the important data binding element that we have used until now.
If you're already familiar with data binding, then all the three things that we have discussed and then
you can skip this video, but if you want to have a quick review of whatever we have. Until now, you
had gone the first data binding element that we had discussed was something called interpellation.
So username.
And what we did was this is called interpolation, right? So be able to say user name.
And what does it do.
It just takes the user name and shows it in here.
So here's one way data binding is taking data from a component property and showing it on The View.
So the second kind of data binding that we did was event binding, which was basically binding event on
The View. A click of the button a user action or event method on the component.
So the two terminology that we made use of until enough is this is a component property.
And this is a component event event binding.
Helps us to bind a view event to component event method.
The third one which we made use of was a data binding.
We just need to do.
a "banana-in-a-box" kind of structure, and we need to put in the property name from the component
So from the component into what it is the property name, we need to put it in here and we saw that this
enables 2-way data binding. What is happening is when the view was loaded, the initial data was coming
in from the component property.
And whenever we change the user name, whenever user enters a new username in28minutesOne or something
of that kind, what would happen?
What happens is the modified data gets binded back to the component property.
You can see that as soon as I type in 123, it's the user name is also getting updated.
This is because what is happening here is this value is bound to the component property user name.
And this is the display of that specific value you look at how it's tied to this anymore.
Ties up whatever data is entered in it, ties up directly to the component property username. What you
think interpolation will do?
It ties up the view to the value of this property.
So what is happening here is as I keep changing this.
You can see the user name value added in here. In this quick video,
what we did was get a quick overview of the three kinds of data binding that we used.
The first one was Interpolation, where we bind in property to view element.
The second one was even binding, where we tie up a user event a click of a button to event which is defined
inside the component.
The component event. The third one was to where data binding implemented using in the ngModel.
They make sure that whatever value which is present for the component property, is tied to the view element
and whatever data which is entered in the view element is automatically tied back to the component property
as well.
One of the interesting things is this ngModel over here is called an Angular directive.
Angular Directive adds additional meaning on top of the typical HTML.
So we know in HTML, type  means this, name means this.
So we do that and let directives and specific things, which add extended meaning to whatever is already
present in HTML.
So this kind of adding on top of whatever is possible using HTML. We look at a lot of Angular
directives a little later.
Let's take a break and I'll see you in the next step.