Welcome back. In the previous step, we looked at a quick review of the types of data bindings that we have
used, and you know there are other kinds of data binding which we were talking about a little later. In
this step,
Let's do some validation around the user name and password.
One of the important things that you need to remember, is the validation that we would introduce in this
basic step, is kind of a hard coded validation,  as you're just getting started with Angular, and we will
want to understand the possibilities.
So let's hard-code stuff in here.
Typically this is not something you do in a production application.
Remember that warning before you would go into this specific step.
Let's move to the login.component.html template, and remove the username info and stuff, which
is present in here.
What I'll do is I'll comment this out,  control-/ or command-/
What do you want to do, is we would want to introduce a validation on the username and password.
What we do for now is we use the handleLogin().
So in the handleLogin() method, what we'll do is we'll introduce the hard coded logic.
What we want to do is when a specific user name and password is entered, which is entered on login, that's
fine but if invalid user name and password are entered, what we want to show is a message saying invalid
credentials at the top.
So how can we show a message saying invalid credentials at the top.
What should we do?
We should go obviously to the HTML, right?
So let's go here, and let's add a simple tag... I used a small font and I'll say Invalid credentials.
Yes.
So what would happen is, let's ensure ... let's put a div around the user name and password so that it's
actually shown on the next line.
Let's wrap them in as well.
Ok cool.
Now let's see what would have been invalid credentials is shown on the top.
The username password.
That's cool.
But the thing is we only want to show invalid credentials in the case of invalid credentials right.
So right now the user has not even clicked the plug in button, and we are showing invalid credentials!
That's not really good.
The other thing is I don't really like, is  the fact that we hardcoded in here.
Let's actually move to the login component ... message ... so I'll call this error message =  'invalid
credentials'
And I would want to use it from the errormessage. How can I use it here?
Simple right.
Interpolation.
Let's put errormessage you would see that it's as usual.
Now in the handleLogin(), let's write a little bit of business logic to it and if I do that and who is
not an invalid user.
So I create a variable here called invalid Login.
Initially it would be false. Let's comment this out... and let's say if this.username ===
In Java we would typically use ==. In javascript.
The safest way to do comparison is to use ===.
So if this.user name === in28minutes and this.password ===
dummy then invalidLogin = true. What are saying is in this kind of scenario.
invalid login is going to false.
This is kind of a mistake which we typically do.
What's the solution.
Think about it what should I do this in javascript.
You always need to use this.
So there's nothing really. login = false, else this.invalidLogin = true. Isn't
this interesting!
Now if I'm saving this... will this make a difference?
Click login... oops!
Nothing is getting printed because we removed that log.
But it's not really toggling the invalid credentials.
Now what I would want to do is I would want to tie this invalidLogin value to the display of this
error message.
How can I do that.
I would want to say should this only if invalid log in is true.
How can I do that? the way you can do that is by adding a ngAttribute, an angular attribute.
As we discussed earlier angler's attributes add additional meaning to HTML, and over here we use something
called ngIf.
So show the element only if valid login. Let's save this and loops you'll see that the invalid log
in message disappeared.
And now I'm going to click log in.
Those are entered in28minutes an empty password chosen in credentials. If I say dummy and say
log in it disappears, and the password log in invalid credentials.
Isn't this cool!
In this step, we enhanced the handleLogin() method with some hard-coded authentication logic
This is not what you do in typical production applications, for now it helps us to get going with Angular.
And what we did is we use this authentication logic to tie up the error message down to and that do
in ngIf.  if we implemented some small business logic and I did.  I'm having a lot of fun introducing all these
concepts to you and I'm sure you are having a lot of fun too.
I'll see you in the next step.