Welcome back. In the previous step, we implemented a little bit of logic and around authentication for
the user name and password.
But instead of a massage saying valid user id and password, what should happen typically I should go to a welcome page.
Right.
But that's not really happening in here.
So when I enter the property user id and password what would happen.
right now we are inside the login component.
What we want to do, is go from the login component to the welcome component.
How do we do that?
That's basically where the routing comes into picture.
You would want to be routed from the login component to the welcome component.
Let's look at the basics of routing, and try and implement a little bit of routing, in this specific video.
When we were creating the Angular application using ng new, one of the questions which we were asked
was do we need routing.
And we said yes, we need routing, and that's where we got a specific file call app routing module.
So this is the module which would handle all the routing for us here out there.
We can define all the routes which we want to use in this specific application.
Let's take an example for the welcome component. I'd want to create a new route.
Welcome. The way you can do that is by defining an object in here.
So I'll def. object.
The first attribute is something called path.
So what is the path, at which you would want be export?
This path is welcome. And which component defines that? The component which defines that is LoginComponent
what you can do is type in LoginComponent, and press enter.
So what it does is, it automatically import the login.component, so that as soon as I press enter.
what would happen is an import is present in here. As we discussed earlier about importing classes from
other modules.
This login.component contains the information for this specific class.
So if ApproutingModule wants to make use of that this specific class... wants to make use of another class, it
needs to be imported.
Actually what we'll do is we'll map the path login to the logging component, and for the welcome component
will map welcome.
So I'm copying these into an array, so you can see that this is within square brackets is an area so I can have
multiple objects separated by a comma.
So now, we are defining a path to the login component as well as to the welcome component.
So what would happen now?
Let's see. If I type in localhost:4200/welcome, what would happen.
You'd see that there are no errors which are being shown but, component just not really shown.
And then say login? the same thing.
The second page has not been shown, the logon page is being shown by default, but there are no errors.
If I say login123, you'll see that there are errors which are shown, because login123 is
not something which we have defined in here.
So it says I cannot match login123, I don't know what is login123
The cool thing is no we see that router is in play, but we were not able to use it yet.
The thing is there is a tag for a router, which you need to use to enable the routing.
Let's go to the app component instead.
That's the first component which is loaded inside here.
Earlier we had commented something called a router-outlet.
What I'll do is just remove this comment,  and just comment out the app-login part right now.
So what we have in here, active is just the router outlet.
So this is the tag which enables the display of whatever output router-outlet is producing.
So you would see when I say localhost:4200 you are not seeing anything because we have not
defined the route for it, but when I say localhost:4200/login, what will you see the login page
and then say localhost:4200/welcome.
You see the welcome page. It says: Welcome works. Another thing I would like to do is inside that routing
module.
Let's add another route for the login component, to path  the default path goes to the login component
right.
So that's what you would want to do.
So even when you type in localhost:4200, it would go to the log in page.
Isn't that cool.
The other thing is when you type in localhost:4200/login and
some garbage.
What is happening?
Oops! You are getting an error! Do you want to this kind of address to your user?
No.
So what we do is we create a component.
Let's go back to a command prompt on the terminal where we are using the ng that command.
Make sure that you are inside the current folder.
So this is a todo project that we are working with.
And I would want to generate and add component to this component would be used as the display page.
When something wrong happens, let's open up error.component.html
It says error works! Some error happens
typically instead of hard coding the text in here, what would we do with that component.
Yes.
And have an errormessage errormessage
an error Occurred
contacts support at ***
and what we'll do is all here use interpolation, interpolation to show the message
if you go here, and type in /garbage.
Error!
What should you do?
We have not really added that component into the routing!
Let's add that to the routing
How do you add it? what we are saying is these are the parts which I defined.
Anything else about it to be a component, but standard component is not important in a need to have a
comma, and say this: command-B and right-click Format.
OK this looks good enough.
Let's go ahead.
And try it again
awesome!
It says Error, contact support.
This page can be further enhanced a little later. In this step.
We implemented routing.
We added routes to all the component to the logging component, at the welcome component, and we also created
an component just in case a user types in garbage.
In reality,  the model you are looking at the app routing module, is responsible for initialization
of the routes.
The other thing which we looked at, was the fact that we needed to add a tag called router-outlet.
This make sure that the traffic control is in the hand of the application.
routing module
We'll talk more about routing as we go on.
I'll see you in the next step.