Welcome back. In the previous step we implemented the basic route.
So when we type in a URL, we were able to directly go to that specific component. Well, what we wanted to
really achieve was when I entered the right password and click login, I wanted to go to the welcome
page.
How do we do that?
That's basically what we would be focusing on in this specific step.
Let's go down to our login component, login.component.ts is where our business logic is. Let's
maximize this.
And now over here, I'd want in this specific situation I would want to re-direct to come here. Now if
I want to redirect to the welcome page, I would need an instance of the router. I would want to use the router which
is currently defined by Angular.
Typically when you look at old code, the way we would do that is by saying, asking something like Angular.
giveMeRouter()
That's basically the way we would do that in our applications.
So if I want router, I would go and get it. In the last few years.
a new concept called dependency injection has picked up a lot of momentum, and it's awesome.
The concept of dependency injection is basically that if I need something, I should declare it as a dependency
and Angular would make sure that the dependency would be given to me.
If you work with frameworks like spring in the Java world, you would already be aware of dependency
injection, and dependency injection is a built-in feature, so you don't really need to add any libraries
or anything of that kind. To add Dependency Injection feature to Angular. Over here, what you want to do.
is you would want to
use the router when any component,
for example here login component, wants to make use of another component.
For example, the router in here, the router is called a dependency.
So router is a dependency of the login component.
And if I want to get the dependency, what I would need to do is I would need to declare it as a constructor
argument.
What we can do here is create a parameter of type.
I'm saying router:Router. What I would want to do, is find it out there and inject it in into
this particular component.
So when I pressed enter, the class was imported in, and as you can see it it's from a module called angular
/router
And so we are importing router here,  and we added a variable in here. What would happen now is and
we take the built in router and make it available in here.
This feature is called dependency injection and it's built in into Angular, in typescript.
Whenever you pass in a parameter to a constructor what would happen is that.
parameter would be available as a member variable.
In Java you'd typically create a variable in here, saying a Router router and after that you would go
here and say this.router is equal to that.
Typically the Java code that we would write, but in typescript you don't really need to do anything. If
you pass something as a constructor argument, it is by default available as member variable.
The important thing is, I would want to add aprivate, so I don't want it to be used outside the specific
class so, I'll add a private router: Router.
And now you would want to redirect the welcome page.
How can we do that?
This router there is a method called navigate(). So the navigate helps us to route to a specific page.
One of the important things that you would need to know, is navigate accepts an array and the first argument
inside this array is the page you want to navigate to. At a later point in time we, look at parameter that
you can pass along with the router.
But for now let's just stick to the basics, and we are just passing in the welcome route. Let's now go to the
browser... in28minutes
Password is empty.
Login credentials as expected, dummy login
Cool!
Now we're going to the welcome page.
So what are the changes that we have made are working.
So we are able to navigate from the login page to the welcome page. In this step, we focused on how to
navigate from the login page to the welcome page. In this step we implemented the navigation from the
login page to the welcome page.
All that we had to do was enhance the login component: we needed to use different injection to inject
the router, and the router is the thing which controls the routing.
And we had to invoke a method called navigate() on the router.
I'm sure you're having a lot of fun and I'll see you in the next step.
Until then, bye-bye!