Welcome back. In the previous step, we implemented the logic to do the routing between the login page
and the welcome page. In this step, what we want to do is we would want to take the username which is present
in here, and show it as part of the welcome message.
One of the ways we can do that, is by adding it as a parameter.
So the route can accept a parameter. Just I can say welcome in28minutes, what I want to do, is I would
want to take in28minutes parameter, and show here saying OK, welcome to this application.
in28minutes, because that's the name which is being passed in.
How do we do that?
Let's look at it, in this specific step.
Let's open up the routing.module.ts, and what we want to say here is you would expect a parameter name. What would
happen from now on, is welcome.
/name would be expected, and that would be routed to the welcome component. now, you need to enhance the  welcome
component to accept that about parameter.
How can we do that? Typically in Angular, you would want to inject whatever dependency I would need
To be able to do that.
The dependency that we would need to be able to do that, is called ActivatedRoute
What is the route that is currently active?
I need to get that.
And from there, I would be able to pick up the parameter which is passed in. How can I do that?
The way I can do that is by saying private route:ActivatedRoute
So we are making it as one of the arguments to the constructor, so that they should be injected in by
the Angular Dependency Injection framework.
There's a compilation error on the ActivatedRoute. Control-space and make sure that you're choosing the
right one.
Make sure that you're choosing the Angular router ActivatedRoute, and click the import of ActivatedRoute
in here so import ActivatedRoute from @angular/route
That's good.
Now from this I would want to pick up the route parameter name.
How can I do that? The way I can do that is by doing this.route.snapshot
So it gives you a snapshot of what the parameter is, which are passed in, and from there I would want
to get the list of items from which I would want to pick up the name parameter.
So let's see if we are able to get this.
Let's do a console.log on this.
If you go to the browser and type in localhost/welcome this would give you an error because now
a welcome is no longer defined. What we have defined is welcomed/name so I need a person name
parameter.
welcome/in28minutes. So what is happening now, is some welcome message is just printed and in28minutes
if te user name was something else, in Angular would it that guys printed.
If I go back to the welcome page and try logging in in28minutes, and dummy, this would give me an error.
It says contact support, because we are redirecting to the welcome page.
We are not putting in the parameter name.
How can we fix that?
Think about it. Just go to the login component and think about how we can fix that.
To app.component.html
How can we fix that?
Actually that should have been too login.component.ts
Does what I can do is I can pass in a  parameter
So after welcome, I can take this.username.
So if you are passing the username as a parameter.
Let's see what would happen.
Go back to login page.
in28minutes, dummy, login.
Cool.
Welcome works!
Now what you wanted to do is, we would want to actually use this in the welcome message. So welcome.component.
html. and over here instead of welcome works,
I would say welcome to our awesome App.
Welcome, and say over here... how can we get the value which is present and the welcome component down here
so we have the name, but how do we show it in here?
What I'll do is I'll create a member variable, so I'll say name = '',  and over here what we do in the
ngOnInit()
let's comment this out, and let's take this and say I need to the name. name =  this....
is this good.
No this is not yet good, because we need to say this doesn't mean that we have the name as part of the
component as a component property.
Now I would want to take it and bind it over here. So what would happen is a welcome in28minutes.
Welcome to our awesome App
login again..
It works.
In this video,
We looked at how to have a routing parameter
So we added a name routing parameter to the welcome route. All that we needed to do was change the
path to add a :name, indicating what the name of the parameter, that would be passed in for that be
and hence the component to inject in the activated route, and pick up the parameter from the route parameter.
Next,
we made it a member variable, and we enhance the view.
welcome view to use that and showed it.
The other thing we had to do was enhance the login component to pass in the parameter which was entered
in by the user.
The user name which was entered in, was passed as a parameter to navigate(). We have been making
a lot of progress.
And I'll see you in the next step. Until then, bye-bye!