Welcome back.
We had created the login component, the welcome component, and for the first time, let's move towards  creating the
list todo component. login  and welcome components are not really perfect yet but let's start with the
list todo component, and after that let's review the work that would be done.
So let's get started with the list todo component.
Obviously the way you would create It is by saying listtodo
And because these are two different words, I would typically capitalize the set list recaps to do this.
So the component ListTodo, and pressing Enter now.
And the component is created.
As usual it's added to the app module.
What it can do, is add a simple link in here which would help us to go to the todos page.
Typically what we would do is as soon as we can get a component, is add a route. else, we will not
be able to get to the component.
Let's open up the AppRoutingModule
Let's add a route. Make sure that you are adding the route about the **.
One of the important things is the order of these routes is really really important.
If you put **above, and you put the new route down below it, what would happen is this ** would
match the component route so because that would match anything, it's a regular expression to match anything.
So this is what I would match and always the error component would be selected. to even if you type
in /listtodos, it might show the error component and that would not be really good.
Right.
What we want to show is the listtodos component. To show listtodos component, import it in, and over
here.
path of todo. So todos redirects to the listtodos component.
We can test that quickly by typing in /todos. could sort of works.
That's good.
Let's open up the list-todos.component.ts
And let's open up the list-todos.component.html.
How do we create objects?
Let's say I want create a simple todo object. The way I can do that is by thing todo = and
type in the content of the todo.
I can say ID is 1.
description is learn to dance.
And so on and so forth. So that you can add an object attribute, and now what I can do, is  that I can take
this, we can display it as part of our list todos. component.
So what I would do, is I would create a simple table. Inside the table,  let's add a caption saying my
todos. we don't really have a lot todos as of now.
But don't worry we will fix that little later.
Add a thead, and typically you have the body inside the thead. In the body, you would have the table.
That's kind of the structure of any table. And you would have a th over here, th. Let's say is the
ID in let's call it this again, and this would be the description
and over here down below, we'll copy the same thing like over here tr's would be used.
So we just have one row for now. That's OK. And tr over here.
So let's do it right click on my document.
Actually I should have done a td down here.
Am forgetting my syntax
That's interesting.
Now we have the tr-td stuff already.
We have a simple id, description : id, description.
If you go to the page.
Yes.
The table is here.
And let's add a border
so we can actually see it. Here instead of the id I would want todo.
How can I do that? I can use interpolation to do that.
Well we're here todo.description
that good. The page.
It says  ID 1 , description learn to dance.
That's cool!
Right so we are able to get the todo data which is present in here, and use it and displayed on the screen.
What we want to do, is we would want to use a list of todos, right.
We want to show a list of todos, not just one to two.
So how do we create a list of todos
todos =  [] array of... todos would be created as an array?
Right?
And this would be one of the todos, which would be part of it. So what we'll do, is we'll define it in
here.
So what the typical way we would do that, is by saying Id:1 : description:
learn to dance. Add another one "to
become an expert at Angular", and maybe another one
"visit India" or whichever country you would want to visit.
OK.
So instead of one todo, we have a list of todos. Comment
This one out, because I don't really want to use this to be anymore. control-/.
How do we map this list of todos to the HTML? So we would want to show here a list of todos. The way you can
do that is by using an ng directive.
So we would want to loop around all the todos. What we would typically use for loop right.
It's called ngFor = what we would want to loop around the todos.
And what we want to do is we would want to create a variable called todo of.
So if I would want to put in the component Java code, then it would be something like for ... it would look
at look something like this: Todo todo: todos
So we are declaring a variable called todo of the type Todo
So the important thing is to use the keyword 'of'. A lot of times people put it 'in', and that would give you
an error.
So it's let space todo of todos
todo is the variable name which we can use inside this template, let and of are keywords
And if you go back to the todos page, you would see that all the todos are populated.
So we see myTodos,  ID, description, 1 to 3, and all that fun stuff.
In this quick video, we added in a list of todos.
We create a competent called todos.
We added a list of to todos, and we enhance our view to show the list of todos. We use a new directive
called ngFor, which is used to loop around.
So what would happen is almost like there is a for loop around this.
So you can almost imagine as if there's a for loop todo: todos around this and that.
So that's exactly what that is.
So you can imagine it as if this is the code which is written so inside the for loop, you have these
there.
And each loop is executed, for each of the todo which is present inside the list of todos.
In the next step, let's enhance this list a little bit more.
Let's bring a few of the best practices into it. And I'll see  you in the next step.