Welcome back. In the previous step, we worked on the todos,  we created todos page,
As of now we don't really have a route from the welcome page to the todos page.
Let's create a simple route between them, using a link.
Let's open up the welcome.component.html, and what we want to do here is we said Welcome welcome to our
awesome App.
And after that what do you want to do, is you can manage your todos here.
And I would want to make it here as a link. So over here, we would want to link to the news page.
Welcome to this page, What I'll do is use something called routerLink.
There is one of the routing directives. So let's see what will happen.
So I said routerLink = /todo.
Let's refresh the page and you can see you can manage your todos here.
Let's put a br out here, just so that it comes in the next line. Or the other option would have been
to just say a div here, put the welcome text within the div, and create another div to have the link
when you wait for the page to refresh.
You would see a welcome page like this, and now I can click here.
And when you go there you see that there is an error.
The reason is because I would have I should have used this slash.
Let's see what would happen let's go back to the welcome page and click here.
Now you see that be able to go to this page, to know what we have is the complete navigation to login
page: in28minutes, dummy.
Once you login, you would go to the welcome page, and in the welcome page you can click here to go to
the todos page.
So we have the navigation built in between the login page,
the welcome page, and the todos page. In this quick step we added a router link so that we
can navigate from welcome page to the todos page.
I'll see you in the next step.
Bye bye.