Welcome back. In this course, we initially created the page we created this kind of an object structure.
The important thing here is we don't really have any class to represent the todo structure.
The best practice is to create two classes to represent the structure, and do that to create the todo.
Let's start doing that in this specific step.
Let's create a class called Todo, as you discussed earlier Javascript module file.
So this file... each file... each typescript file is javascript module, and in this file, you can have any
number of classes created.
So let's create one more class export class.
Let's call this Todo.
And in this class I would want to create a.
So you could have a constructor created with a few parameters, allright. With these parameters must be
public. Let's start with creating the ID, so id:number it has public description, description is the string
next for each todo,  you would want to maintain when it's completed or not.
You call this done, and the type of this is boolean.
And the last one which I would want to happen.
Each todo has a target date.
When do you want a completed by the date, and the target date will have it as a date.
Now the constructor is already one of the important typescript.
Each of these constructor arguments becomes a member when you create the object of this piece.
So let's see what would happen here.
I can do now instead of this new todo of 1, the next one is the description so I can copy into
learn to dance
have the id, we have the description and the next one is is it done or not.
No it's not done yet.
I would still need to do it.
And new Date... I created a new date and I copy this again.
Now let's say the next todo is 2, and let's say the next one is to 'become an expert at English'.
I'm not sure if it's true or false.
Let's leave it at false.
And the last one is 3, 'visit your favorite country'.
You can decide whether you have completed the visit or not.
I'll comment this out, and learn what is coming down here.
What we are doing is moving away from an unstructured format to being structure.
We are creating a class to represent that todo.
And let's update the todos competent so that we have to do. What I need to that description that
does not really need to change.
Let's see what would happen.
You'd see that when you press refresh, things are still working what I would want to do is I would
want to update the field to which we are showing right now.
I don't think anybody would care about the ID, so let's throw the id out, and what we add in is description.
And let's make it a capital D,  the let's add target date
and let's add in another one
is Completed, and let's add them in to the description todo.targetDate.
todo.
let's see what happens.
You can see now my todos: description, target date and is completed.
And now you can see that this is not really well formatted especially the target date.
Target date.
We will want to format it for that.
So we use something called a pipe.
So what we have is a field.
So this field value you would want to format it as a normal date.
What would happen now? let's do a refresh, and you can see that this is the default format of date.
There are a number of things that you can use pipe for. pipe is basically a way you convert one value
into another format.
Here we are saying we want to convert it into a normal date format. If you would want to have everything
in uppercase, you can say uppercase again. You would see that everything.
So nov eight now appears in, NOV is in caps. Or if you'd want everything it would be in lowercase
you can do lowercase.
So these are all called pipes, and pipes are used to convert one field in one format to another format
and you'd want to do to lowercase with the field, you would use a pipe so you can see that everything
is in lowercase.
Don't worry about the lowercase, I'll remove it.
What we have now is a relatively well designed todo page In this step, we created the class constructor
and.
We created a number of todos, and we used the component to display them.
We used a couple of pipes to convert the target date into a more visually appealing format.
I'm sure you are having a lot of fun.
We are taking a lot of rapid strides in the last few steps, and I'll see you in the next step.
Until then, bye bye.