Welcome back.  until now,  I've created a number of components: component... login component and welcome component
list-todos component, and we saw that whenever we created a component using ng generate component.
Each time the component was getting added into an NgModule, which was app module
This app module has an additional NgModule on it, which stands for Angular Module. Anything attached
to the ng is Angular, so Angular Module.
So let's discuss what is NgModule doing, and how were Angular modules are different from javascript modules.
When you think about Angular applications, they are built using a number of angular modules
Some of the angular modules are built into angular framework, so you can see FormsModule, AppRoutingModule
BrowserModule, NgModule.
All of these are built in angular modules, inside the angular framework.
Whenever we need to use any of the angular features, we needed to import that specific module in.
If you remember in the login.component.html, we want to use the module data, to and then be added
in the module, that gave us an error.
And what did we do at that particular point in time?
We imported the FormsModule.
So if you want to use any of the building features in angular, we need to import the corresponding angular
module for it.
That's what we observed until now. In summary, all the components that we created until now, are
associated with this Angular module called app module. and whenever we needed to use some other feature from
Angular, we needed to import the specific module.
Thing is, when we think about Angular's applications, you should always think about them as a group of
angular modules. Each component,
Each directive that you create as part of the angular application are always associated with angular.
Module. If you look at the syntax of the angular module, it starts with an '@' , @NgModule decorator
what the declaration is saying is these five things are part of this specific Angular module.
So if some other application wants to reuse the error component, or it wants to use the logging component
What do they need to do?
They would need to make use of this NgModule, so they would need to import the module in and only
then they will be able to make use of the specific component.
The second attribute what you're seeing here is import. import is nothing but the components and directives
of this specific model.
What you are saying is component in the app model will need all these modules to work.
So we said we need the app.module, we need the browserModule we need the module.
We talk about providers a little later when we talk more about dependency injection.
The last one that just isn't in here is something called Bootstrap.
Then this module is loaded, which component should be loaded as well.
Those are called the bootstrap component.
We have Appcomponent listed in as a bootstrap component in here.
So what we have discussed until now is the fact that the module is a group of components are that active
which are dedicated for a specific purpose, and that module is the fundamental block of use in an
angular application.
If you go through the components, you would need to import the corresponding angular module you.
One of the question is, how was the more different from a javascript module? The first important thing
is you has the annotation in angular, and it is used to group angular component, angular building blocks.
A javascript module is a file.
So just any of this module that these files can open into these files, or be created a lot of component
of these files until now.
So all this component.ts files login.ts, error.ts, welcome.component.ts
Each of these each file is a module. You can create any number of classes in the module. You can create
any number of functions in that specific module.
So each of these things that you are looking at is a Javascript module. In comparison an angular module
is something which has @NgModule... annotation on it. Javascript module is used to group different
elements which are present in a single file, whereas an angular module is used to group different angular
Components, or different angular building blocks. This angular component might be actually defined in a
separate file as well.
In this video, we quickly looked at the concept of an angular module and compared it with javascript model
An Angular module is a grouping of a number of angular building blocks like components.
I'll see you in the next step.
Until then,
Bye bye.