Welcome back. In one of the previous steps, we saw that when we run ng serve inside the todo folder, we
were able to launch up the angular application, and we were able to look at it in the browser. In this
step, let's explore ng serve further,  as well as let's look at a few other ng commands.
that you can run from your command line.
I would want to look at a file called index.html in the source.
So let's go to the source index.html . Inside this file is the title.
So you'll see that To Do.
This is where it's coming from.
So let's go ahead and change this to something else, let's say My To Do Application, and I'm saving it
right now.
What happens is you would see that I'm not doing anything on the browser right now.
Within a little while, you'd see that it's auto-loaded. That's what ng serve does. ng serve would
keep pulling your code for changes.
And as soon as there is a change, it would pick up, build it and it would load it into the browser.
Let's do another example let's go to source app... app.component.html.
This is where the actual content of this page is coming from.
Welcome to To Do, the the logo as well as the links which are present in here.
For the most part, this is typical html, except for something called interpollation which is being used
in here.
We'll look at it a little later.
But for now let's remove the , and the . So i'm removing the links which are present in here
and saving it. You would see that immediately the change is reflected on the browser.
That's the most important thing that ng serve brings onto the plate.  So as soon as  you are making a change.
You can see it reflect on your browser.
Now let's look at a few other commands. ng
lint. ng lint. When you ran it, it would say linting, and it would finally print that.
There are no violations which are present,  and so the question you might ask is what is linting? Who's doing the
linting?
Linting is nothing but checking your code for coding standards.
Because the code which we have is generated, we did not write a single line of code by hand.
Yet all these files pass the coding standard. What we do now, is we introduce a coding standard violation.
How can I introduce a coding standard violation? Go to Visual Studio Code, open up a file called app.
component.
This is the way you can open a file, is by searching through the explorer, and finding it and opening
it, or you can press command-B or control-B.
If you are on Mac, it's command-B, and if you are on Windows it's Control-B. You can type in app.component
.
Yes.
And you should be able to load that specific file into the UI.  You'd see that at the end of every typescript
file.
There is a newline character. What I'll do is remove the new line characters so now this file has
only 10 lines.
Let's go to the terminal and do ng lint.  What you see is that it would say there is a file which has
a problem. Aha!
It says: Lint errors found in the listed files... it says error: app.component.ts file should end
with a new line, that what is the standard.
Now you might be wondering where are all these rules defined.
All these rules are defined inside a file in our project, which
is tslint.json.
This is where all the rules are defined, and the end of file rule that we looked at, is defined on line
17, right.
So it's "eofline":true. So it should make sure that at the end of the file there is a newline character
The great thing about this file, is the fact that you can customize it according to the needs of your
particular project.
Now that I added the new line, I can do ng lint, and you would see that there are no errors.
Let's get back to the command line, and let's run a few more.
Let's go on to the next command which is ng build.
What does the ng build do?
Let's run it and see what's happening.
What you see is when you run ng build, it says there are specific files created main.js,  polyfills.js,
runtime.js, styles.js,  vendor.js,  and when you go to the IDE, you see that there
is a new folder which is present in here, which is the dist folder.
If you open up the dist, you would see a few files which are present in here, in this main.js, and
all that kind of stuff.
The good thing about this folder, is you can take this todo folder,  and put it behind any web server and
you'd be able to launch index.html, and run the application.
So you don't really need any of the other code which is present in here, to launch these angular applications.
Typically when we deploy angular applications to production, what we would do is we would execute in dist.
And we would take this folder which is generated and put it on the web server.
So into this, it makes it easy to deploy applications to other environments. For example, test environments,
or production, or... All you need to do is to copy this to other environments.  The next command which we are going
to look at is ng test. We only write applications, we are supposed to write a lot of unit tests and
you test runs the unit tests which are written. For angular applications typically, unit tests for angular
are written in a framework called Jasmine, and we're using karma to run the unit.
You can see that all the tests ran, and there are zero failures. In front-end language, tests are called
specs.
So these specifications.
What are they running?
And you can see what are the specifications which ran. App Component should create an app. App component should
have a title To Do. App Component should render title in a  tag. If you want to run any of the specificications
again, you can click them, or you can click the app on it to run this again.
Let's quickly look at where these tests are defined.
There are a few important files that related to unit tests.
The first one is the karma.conf.js.
This is the configuration of the test-runner, which is. karma. Other than that, there are a number of tests
which are written as part of your angular code.
Typically these files would have an extension .spec . The spec stands for specification.
That's basically the test.
And if you open up the spec file, you should see all the tests which are written.
So these are the tests which ran earlier.
So you can see all the tests which are present in here.
And let's exit this by saying control-C.
Now the other command which is present in here is ng e2e.
e2e stands for ng End-to-end.
So end-to-end. There's much more than the unit tests. unit tests test individual components one at a time.
with end-to-end tests, what happens is we would launch the entire angular application, you can see that we are
launching the angler application at localhost:4200.
It's still building up.
It might take a little while.
So now, the application has been launched up. And now you would see that we are actually running the entire application
and running these tests around it. You'd see that over here, it's showing display a message and it says one
test successful.
If you look at the logs you would see that there was something called a chrome driver which was downloaded
which is actually something related to the selenium automation.
Yes the chrome driver was installed, and the chrome driver was used to launch up the tests in the end to end
mode.
I'm using a framework called protractor. protractor is a layer around the selenium API which helps us to
write and do end-to-end tests. In this course, we will not be focusing on either the unit tests, or the end to end tests.
All the code for the end to end tests is present inside this folder.
And all here you would see also the protractor.conf.js.
So this is the configuration for protractor, which is an end to end integration testing later, which
is present in here as well. The file which defines what should happen when run a specific command. So we
ran a number of commands, right?
ng test, ng build, ng lint.  The angular.json file is where all these commands are defined. In this
video,
We looked at a few commands which we can execute from the command line, which are provided by Angular CLI.
We looked at ng lint, which is to execute coding standards.
We saw that there is a file called the lint.conf.js, on where all the lint rules all decoding standards
are specified.
Next we ran ng build, and we saw that a disk folder was created which contains all the files, which should
be sufficient to deploy this specific application to external external environment.
We ran ng test, which ran all the unit tests which were created using the jasmine framework in the .spec.js
files, using the runner, which is defined as part of the karma.conf.js
After that we ran the command ng e2e, and and all the tests which were defined in the end to end
folder were executed.
We saw that the entire application was launched up, and protractor was used to run the end to end tests.
The idea behind this basic video is to give you a big picture or view of all the commands,  and what are
the files associated with them.
You might not really need to understand all these files in depth. It's sufficient to know where they
are, and what they're related to.
And that's good enough for now.
I'll see you in the next step.
Until then, bye-bye.