Welcome back. In the previous few steps we created a few components.
One of the things we did, was we did not really discuss in depth is what is happening when you load a page
how we use this specific component getting around. let's discuss that in this video.
In this specific step what we're discussing is called bootstrapping. Often angular application and the
bootstrapping of an angler application, there are two things which play a crucial role the root Module
and the root component.
Let's understand what is bootstrapping, root model and root component.
If you do right-click View page, on this page you see this index.html, which is being loaded
you can see app-root present in here.
So what is happening here is the first file is index.html.
And in parallel to that, there is a file called
main.ts.
If you look at this main.ts, what we are doing in here is we are loading up app module.
So we're importing the app module in, and we are bootstrapping it, which ever module is the one which
is first bootstrapped in an angler application is called the root Module.
That's the reason why we call app module the module when root module gets initialized.
If you look at the module, you would see that along with the module that are we in...
we are initializing the app component in the bootstrap. we are finding that it's the app component
and therefore the app component also get bootstrapped, it get ready to be loaded.
And what we are doing in index.html is loading up the app component.
If you look at the app component, you would see that the tag associated with it is app-root, and that
what is present in index.html
What is going on here is that module is getting initialized one, app module is initialize the app component
gets initialized and index.html the app-root.
That's basically the tag of the app component, is getting initialized once we go there.
We get the app.component.ts for whatever it is in the app.component.html, it becomes the
view source.
What we see here is rendered. But what is in app.component.html, becomes the main part of the
screen.
So what I do here is, say todo application and I'll put a few br.
After this you can see that the todo application and below that is the router-outlet.
And if I type in in28 minutes, dummy, right...  and password you'd see that the application header will
remain right there.
The rest of the content is changing but the application remains as it is in there, because that one which
is loaded by the app component.
app.component.html is loading up this, as well as the router-outlet so if I would have something
like todo application header here, and if I have todo application footer in here, it can actually be
a header.
or a menu, right... I can have some aspect of it as well.
What would happen?
You would see that you would have the header, footer, and you would have the content in between.
Go back and let's type in in28minutes, and dummy, so you'll have a header.
The content of the page, and the footer. header, content of the page.
footer! You can see that the header and footer are not changing at all, they are constant.
The only things which are changing the content of the page.
So in summary, what is happening is the app module is the module which gets looked at first, app module which
would load the app component. When the app component is loaded in the end, HTML because of this
app root.
The app.component.html is what is rendered.And we  see router-outlet because of the router-outlet
and the fact that in the app-routing.mosule.ts, we said the default path matched to log in component.
What happens, is inside the router, the login component is first initialized and that's why when you
do this for localhost:4200, you would see the login component first. In this video, we focused on the
bootstrapping of an angular application.
We looked at the root module, is getting loaded that did have the root component is getting loaded, and
we saw how the content inside the component plays a important role.
I'll see you in the next step.
Until then, bye bye.