Welcome back.
Before we go any further, let's review all the concepts that we have learned during the last few steps.
Angular applications are built using a number of angular modules.
There would be a custom built angular modules, which I built as part of your application as well as in
built Angular modules. Which you make use of. If you want to reuse a component, you would need to import
these specific Angular Modules
Whenever you create Angular components,
You need to associate it with an angular module.
So the application is built up of Angular modules, which in turn is nothing but a set of angular component
or directives or building blocks of angular.
Each component has a template which is basically a HTML file where typical HTML
is combined with a few angular specific things, like angular binding syntax right.
We looked at interpolation.
Look at 2-way binding. We looked at event binding as well.
The style CSS part of it, because it is basically the place where we put all the data in as well
as how should we react to the view actions.
So we'll put methods which help us react to view actions the different data binding features in Angular
help us to bind the template to the code. To be able to bind the view, the HTML, to specific data and specific
event which are described in the code.
We also looked at routing, which helps us mainly get from one component to another.
We also made use of a number of ng directives, angular directivess and the forms. We made use of ngIf,
ngFor. We made use of the pipes. While we learn a lot of things in the last few steps, there are a lot.
of things remaining as well.
Other things is look at the design of the pages.
Right now they don't really look appealing.
We would want to use something like bootstrap, we would want to create a few proper menus.
You don't have a proper footer.
The other important thing is there is no security for the menus at all.
If I did localhost:4200/todo, you'd be able to look at the list of those you don't really have
to log in to be able to see the todos.
I don't need to really do this, and go and click this to go to those even without logging in.
If I go to a new page, and type in todos, I will be able to still see the todos. it's highly secure.
The other thing is hardcoded. Logic of the ToDo list is hardcoded.
It's not really coming from the rest API or something of that kind.
The same is the case with authentication.
We have a hard coded logic which is present in there, and there is a lot of Todo functionality which
is remaining to create it.
We need to be able to edit, view and delete Todo's and add todo's, and we have not even started creating
the basics of a piece, with springboot and spring security.
There are a lot of work ahead of us and in the future steps.
Let's focus on getting things done one by one.
I'm really excited to go on this journey of building a full stack application with you and I'll see
you in the next step.