Welcome back. In the previous two steps, the focus was on getting things working.
We were able to quickly get started with creating a simple login page, a welcome page, and mytodos
page.
The focus of the next few steps is on building up on what we already have, and giving it a nice look
and feel.
Have a nice navigation menu and footer.
Use bootstrap to style everything out.
Have proper security systems so that not everybody would be able to get into todos without logging
in, and to refactor some of the stuff that we did to separate some of these components.
I'm sure this would be an interesting refactoring journey and I'll see you in the next step. Bye bye!