Welcome back.
One of the things which we would want to do starting now, is make use of a framework called Bootstrap.
bootstrap is one of the most popular CSS frameworks.
It helps us to design our pages in a very attractive way, as you can read in here.
Bootstrap is world's most popular framework for building responsive sites.
What we do is really use bootstrap from a content delivery network.
So we just need to search for and package bootstrap for packages.
One of the content delivery networks from which we can pick up this is this file as it is.
So what I'll do is pick up the 4.1.0. Any version which is greater than 4.1.0 should
be fine.
I'm going to take the CSS,  and I'm going to use the min.css file,  which is present...
bootstrap.min.css.
You can see that this size is much smaller than the bootstrap.css, because it's a minified version.
So let's take this and we'll use this in our application.
We would want to use bootstrap across the application.
So what I'll do is I'll put it in the styles.css, the styles.css  this is at the root of
the project inside the source tree.
So inside the source, you have style.css at the root and  the styles inside
this is applicable to the entire angular application. If you need to import this in, is by saying at
@import... this is basically CSS syntax... and you can specify the url, is what we see in here.
Yes.
I've not saved it yet.
Let's save the page. Before saving it,
It looks something of this kind.
And let's save it and let's see the page after that.
You can see that the font have become a little bigger.
There is much more space.
And also you would see that the look off of the pages also would improve a little bit, not a lot.
A little bit.
Now what I want to do is also add a menu and a footer as well.
Let's create a couple of components for the menu and the footer.
We use the second command prompt that we already have.
What do you want to do, is in general make sure that you are inside the todo folder.
So ng generate component type menu, will put menu at the top... so it will create the menu component.
That's done... enough!
I would want to also create the footer component.
Now what I want to do is at the top of every page, we would want the menu and the footer.
How can we do that?
What I can do is, I can go to the root component... component. What is it app.component.html.
If you look at the menu component, your component.html says menu works! . I'll just replace this buy
Top Menu Element , and for now let's just put a BR.
BR.
Not the best thing to do, but we'll replace this very soon and we will have footer.component.html.
And what we'll do over here, is also FOOTER,  and before the footer,  we'll put a couple of BR's. what we want to
do with include this component in menu.
And footer.  Think where would we add them in?
I would recommend you to pause the video in here and try and do it as an exercise.
We to add it in the app.component, which is where we would want to define our header and footer.
How would we do that?
Pause the video here, and think about it
I would want to add the menu component here.
And the footer component below it.
How do we do that?
OK let's look at the menu.component here.
What's the tag name?
It could be app-menu.
So what we need to do is go to the app.component.html, and replace this this stuff with an app
-menu. and What so you do with the footer? Loot at footer.component.ts... app-footer. right? Let's see how the page
looks right now.
So you have the top menu element, this thing, and the footer.
What we have now, is the basic elements of any that page: like you have a top menu or component, you
have a footer component, and you have the actual content, and if you go to the page we can go and login
you would see that the top in your element and footer remain as it is. Now I enter login values
the middle of the... content of the of the page changes.
Now I click here, and then you would see that the content on the page changes again. In the next few
steps, we'll add elements to them, and you will add things to the footer and will make the content of the page
much  more formatted.
I'll see you in the next step. Until then, bye!