Welcome back.
This is how the page looks like right now. In this step, let's format a few of the elements on the screen, so
that they look much better.
Let's start with the top menu.
I'm going to visual studio code.
This is where our menu component is coded in. Let's make a list of things that we would want to do.
By HTML5 standards,  the menu should be in something called a header, and inside a class, inside a element
called head.
All our elements should come inside nav.
So let's move this stuff out, and let's try and put a list of elements that I would want to have in here.
So first create a div and inside this div, I would put the name of the application or the
brand or something like that, and let's create a link for that.
So href= this, and instead put in this. Let's just say this is like the UI of the website.
https://www.in28minutes.com.
Maximize the page and over here, we would want to show a list of menu items.
What we want to show is, we want to list items here and to list items.
At the end. We'll show home, and let's say todos here, and log in and log out at the corner.
So I create an ordered list. Actually should have started with that list and inside that would be... yes
each of those lists would contain links.
So let's create that a href= ""
where it needs to link, to the link.
There are a few bootstrap classes that we need to add.
So I'll add them in. Wehn something represents the navigation bar in Bootstrap, the class do you need to add
is navbar.
And I would want to expand all the list elements which represents what I would need to show. I will expand
this part of navigation of the navbar, so I need to say
navbar-nav
And this is one of the links which is present.
So they should be navbar-link.
So what we are doing is just having a few standard bootstrap classes. I would recommend you to look up
the bootstrap documentation if you want to understand this further.
I am no means an expert at bootstrap, but I really like the application to look a little better than
what we have right now.
So let's quickly add a few things.
So if you save and refresh the page you'd see something at the top.
And I think that's how it's reflecting  as of now enough to create a couple of links Let's call this home.
And this would be to do with it. See what would happen.
So you can see in28minutes,  home, todos at the top that's cool. And what we'll do is we'll
have another set of links going up, so you'll see all this stuff at the top.
You just need to add a few more classes to make them appear beautiful.
Before that let's add the home link. What's the link to the home page?
/welcome.
Fair enough.
hard-code this value, right?
So /welcome/in28minutes, /todos,  would be the link for todos,and /login would be the link
for login.
We did not create the log out page yet.
We'll create it a little later, we'll put /logout.
One of the things I have done wrong, is actually this class should be nav-link.,not
navbar-link.
Let's fix that.
And let's see how it looks on the page.
So you have in28minutes,  home, todos, login, logout
That's cool.
This link is the link of the brand.
So let's add a class called navbar-brand. and move in28minutes to the next line. Cool. in28minutes
is now little more highlighted.
We would want this log in and log out to appear at the end of the page, or at the right hand corner of
the page.
So what we need to do is add something like navbar-collapse, and another class justify-content-end.
and now you have in28minutes, the two links here, login and logout in the corner.
Now I would want to give a dark background to this screen, so I'll say it navbar-dark, and I would
want to change the background to dark.
So you'd see that the background is cool!
You have all the links present.
So we have our menu very well designed.
What we were looking at in this specific step, is how we have to design a menu.
If you are good at this then it should have been easy for you.
But if you did not know bootstrap before, then some of these classes might be new.
You can look up bootstrap documentation for information about these classes.
But the purpose of all this thing was to get a good looking header, and that's what we were able to do,
in this specific step.
We will look at more stuff in the next step. Until then, bye!