Welcome back. In this step, let's start focusing on the footer. Let's go down to the footer component, and let's
start with creating a footer.
So let's create a footer inside it, to create a div, and let's create a container div
inside it.
Let's put All Rights Reserved
At whatever thing that you would want to put it in here, and you can maybe put here.
This is how the page looks like right now.
We have a footer at the bottom.
What I would want this, to be here.
So I would want a fixed position for this footer.
What we do is we add a little bit of CSS for that.
What we'll do is we'll open up the footer components CSS.
So this is specific to just the footer.
So we are adding it directly in the footer component, and what we want to do, is what we want to do?
We want to have absolute position.
Actually it's position absolute. What we want as it should be at the bottom of the page. Let's give it
a width,
and a height.
It should be 40 pixels.
It's.
And let's give it a darker background color #222222.  OK.  and let's see what would happen.
Oops!
We did not add the class.
That's the reason why it's not really formatted. .class =  footer.
OK.
Nice.
Now you can see the footer at the bottom,  but I'm not able to see the text.
All right.
I'll go to the footer component, and expand on this.
span
would say class=text-white.
Now you can see the footer down here.
I think it's a little too bright, so let's not really use text-white.
Let's make it a little muted.
Now you have this down here.
That's nice.
You have a header that's cool.
Let's now focus on the actual content of the page.
Let's go to the root component app.component.html, and over here, what I'll do is I'll include
the actual content of the page in div.
Typically if you put something in a container, then it would be appearing with a little bit of padding
and stuff.
So are like putting stuff in a container, so it can put the main content of the page inside a container
div, and what we'll do is we'll go to the todos.component, and we'll add a class onto this.
So we'll remove the border=1.
And let's say class=todos, and what we do is we'll have h1, and  then type in.
So this would be to My Todos.
And with the caption... we don't really need the caption any more.
And next what I'll do is I'll put a little bit of div again.
The class=container, so I'll put the table as well.
Another div.Let's do that.
And save it.
And now this looks much better right.
The class I should have added in here should be table. It's now
good enough. the todos page looks much better than what it was earlier.
Let's do this stuff on the login page, so that quickly as well.
So what we want to do is we want to add a h1 saying This is Login.
And I'll put it here.
The class is equal to container
and let's repeat this over here.
A few things more, What i'll do is use something called the
bootstrap has this concept called alert.
So we'll use those.
That class is called alert, and this would be a warning alert, which is an error message.
Try doing that and over here, all the other stuff.
Kind of looks good.
That's good.
Put the login page and see how it looks.
Cool! login page.
The only thing which I don't really like is the login button.
Let's add a class onto this button as well.
So that's at a class=btn and btn-success.
Now we have a login.
Now the login page looks relatively well-designed, good enough and you can see you can go in here.
Let's call the welcome page, and design it a little bit. What i'll do is is remove this chunk between this. Let's have just
one line
welcome, and that should be fine.
And let's add a class=container, and let's add an h1.
OK! welcome! It says welcome in28minutes
it goes here and management todos, the home link works,  todos link works.
login link works. in28minutes.
Dummy will be able to log in.
Now you'll see that most of the stuff on this page looks much better than what it was earlier in the
last two steps.
We used a little bit of CSS, little bit of bootstrap to make these pages look better.
Bootstrap is definitely not the focus of this course, but even then if you search for bootstrap, for you'd
be able to get to this website, where you have a lot of information about bootstrap, and a lot of examples
as well.
I recommend you to spend some time with all this stuff and all,  some time later.
For now let's focus on Angular. And I'll see you in the next step.