Welcome back. In the previous step, we created the menu, we created the footer, and we saw that all of
them are working fine.
One of the things you would have observed, is when I'm clicking home the page, is getting refreshed now
when I click log in the back page is getting refreshed.
That's because of one thing which we did in the header earlier, what was it? Let's open up the menu component
menu.component.html, for each of these links.
What we did was we had href on them.
What href does is it reloads the entire page.
What we are developing in here, is a single page application.
Right? We don't really want to reload everything all the time. The way we should have done this by saying
routerLink. if you do routerLink, Let's say little more more later.
So I I'm replacing href with routerLink everywhere.
And now if the page reloads, when I click /home to login and logout.
logout would not work obviously.
We have not really built it yet.
So you see that the page does not get refreshed.
The only thing that gets refreshed is the content within that specific thing.
So that's very important.
The reason why I created a separate video, is I wanted to explicitly point out this error, because
this is very important.
We are developing single page application and we don't really want everything to be refreshed.
So whenever you are putting a link out to an internal application thing within the angular application,
use the router link, do not use href. If you use head href, then the page gets fresh.
And that's not really good.
When you go to an external site like an administrator, you don't really have an option.
You have to use a href.
Because it would anyway reload the entire page but for the internal site links.
don't use href, always use that routerLink.
That's the tip I wanted to leave you with in this specific video.
I'll see you in the next one.
Until then, bye!