Welcome back. As of now, all the authentication logic is present in this specific component.
Within the login component.
It does the authentication, and it leads to the welcome page.
The other thing which we see, is the links appear .. the same links appear on all the pages irrespective
of whether somebody is logged in or not.
Our aim in the next few steps is to fix this.
We would want a proper menu, where when a user is logged out, I don't want to see the login menu item
and nothing else.
When he logs in, I would want to see all the menu items except for login, and I would only want to be
able to click the todos or home page links.
Then the user is logged in.
If somebody comes in and typed this URL without logging in, then I don't really want them to log
in, and to make that journey happen.
What you need to do, is you need to have a little bit more authentication logic. We should be able to
authenticate the user, identify that somebody is authenticated, and show the appropriate links and things
like that.
And to help us do that, we would need to have a separate authentication. That is one of the things that
we really focus on in this case, is having good maintainable code.
If I write every piece of hard-coded logic in the same component, then it becomes unmaintainable over a period
of time, and authentication anyway.
is something which is common to all these things.
So what would start doing now is we would create a service.
When do you want to create some logic, which is common across multiple components.
What we would do is we would create a service, that gets started creating authentication. So easy right?
Now we have been creating a number of components ng component.
The way you could create a servies is by typing  ng generate service,  for now, we would use hard coded authentication
to call this in general, so it is hard coded authentication.
Later we would switch to other forms of authentication like basic authentication,  JWT authentication.
So I would really want to be specific about naming service as hardcoded authentication, that's present.
Be careful about how you name the service.
I don't really need to put the word service in there. So now what's happening here, is it created a service
it created a service directly in the app folder, hardcoded authentication.service.ts.
So if you open this file up, it's just a simple class except for the fact that there is an @Injectable
tag on it.
Before we go any further with this one of the things, I would want to fix is the fact that both these
classes are created directly in the root.
So these are directly created in this src folder.
Over a period of time, this makes it really difficult to maintain that kind of stuff.
So be careful, don't really create anything directly in the source folder or look for enough.
I'll delete these.
The way we can create this service folder is by saying service/.
So be careful of which / you should be using.
This is the / you should be using.
The other \ will not work.
So we /hardcoded authentication. You'd see that this is created in the service folder.
So now you have had hardcoded authentication so this created the down here.
When I open it in, you would see that this is a usual normal class except for the @Injectable.
The injectable is what makes this a service.
What happens is, I can use this and I can inject this in any place I would want to use.
Before we discuss this any further, let's create a simple method in here, and let you use that to authenticate
let's say authenticate and say username,  password
and go to login.component.ts.
Yes and get the logic from there.
So it says the logic of authentication is right in here.
So what I would want to do is, I would want a more specific thing.
So it should not be if user, let's use username.
Let's be consistent.
Everywhere it should have the  same name. So the username is in28minutes, and password == dummy.
What we want to do.
Return true. This is authenticated, else then false.
Right.
So this is a service.
What is this service doing? It would provide the authentication logic to you.
So this is where doing the authentication logic.
Now if I want to make use of the service in another component, I would need to make use of dependency
injection.
What injectable does is make this component available for dependency injection.
So this component would be ready, and wherever we find it in the constructor it would be injected in
this would be taken care of by the angular dependency injection framework. For us to tell that this class
needs a specific dependency, we need to add it to the constructor. What do we need to do?
LoginComponent needs to hard-code that authentication service, because we would want to do the authentication
using this specific method now.
So let's go ahead and say private
hardcodedAuthentication and we use :HardcodedAuthentication , so compilation error because I
have to import it in. control-space, and import it in.
Now if you'd see that it's important at the top, you can see that it lets you access that specific
thing.
Cool.
Now we have injected the hardcodedAuthentication, are we use in this line after making a copy of it.
And over here what we want to do is, now I would want to make use of the hardcoded authentication
service.
Actually for that,  try out hardcoded authentication service that authenticates,  and pass in these
parameters
What are the parameters that we need to pass in the store to use that? name.
, this.username ,
this.password.
So what we are doing is moving the logic. We are moving the authentication logic out to HardcodedAuthentication
service.
So if it's authenticated properly, then the route,  or the ways in when they log in is equal to true.
Let's see what would happen if I go to the login page and enter an invalid password: invalid credentials!
That's cool! in28minutes, dummy, login.
That's cool!
This is working perfectly. What we did in this step is, we created a service the hardcoded authentication
so we use the hardcoded authentication, so we have enhanced it with an authenticate method.
We saw that this is available at the root level.
Therefore wherever this dependency is defined inside the constructor.
And would inject it in, and we use that to authenticate the user and for that and look at a wide variety
of stuff. I'll see you  in the next step. Bye bye!