Welcome back. In the previous step,  we made login component to make use of the authentication service . When
a user logs in the login component would talk to the authentication service, and find out if the user
is an authenticated user.
For now we have hard coded logic.
What we want to do, is we would want to enable and disable these links based on whether a user is already
logged in or not. And to be able to do that, we need to be able to check if a user is already logged
in.
Each of these links I should be able to check: is the user logged in? is user logged in?
The thing is right now, we don't really have to store the fact that the user has all logged in.
What we do is we'll use something called session storage in that setting.
So this is something which is associated with the browser window.
It allows us to access the session storage object.
It's actually very similar to something else called local storage.
However this is just limited to this browser session. When you close and come back the session storage
is refreshed. What we'll do is when it logs in, we'll put some content into the session storage, and for all other purposes.
We'll keep checking if the session storage contains the authenticated user.
Let's see how to do that in this specific step.
Now let's go to the authenticate method and over here,
If the logging is successful, what I would want to do is ,sessionStorage.setItem()... I want to say
authenticatedUser, username .What would happen? Whenever the user is authenticated, the authenticated
user is set into the session storage.
Now let's do it again in28minutes,
Dummy login.
What happens now is the login... when you do it right click inspect.
If you go to the Applications tab, you would see that there are a number of kind of storage, there is local
storage, session storage. What we were talking about is this this is specific to this browser
session. If you close the browser and come back, then most of the information is in here it's lost.
If you expand this particular session storage, you'd see that for our localhost:4200,
We have something stored in here: in28minutes.
So you can see the value which is stored into the local storage, and based on this we would want to enable
these menu items.
How can we do that? What we'll do is we'll start with creating a simple method. We'll say we'll call this
isUserLoggedin
what we'll do, is we'll try and get the item from the session storage. So let's get the item from the
session storage sessionstorage. getId(). After this what do we need to check? user = this.
You say let user = this specific thing, and we will check if user
==
If user == null then user is not logged in.
Well what we'll do is we'll say !(user == null).
What I do now, is I'll go here and try and clear this out.
So let's clear this out.
So what we are doing is we are reading the value out for the session storage. You don't really have
anything in there.
What I do is I'll check this method before and after authentication.
So what I'll do is console.log(isUserLoggedIn()). you should say this.
What does that mean?
And what we'll do, is we'll do the same thing after calling .so I'll call this
before, and I'll call this after. Just leave a space here as well.
Let's go back to the login page in28minutes,  login.
So it says in Invalid Credential!! , because the The thing is invalid and you can see it: before false
because it is false.
This does not get executed.
So the value is not set into session storage.
So if you look at application session storage, there are no values which are present in here.
If I said Dummy and say login, let's see the console. You can take before false and after.
true. now!
It's setting
So the value is already inside the session storage.
Let's look at it right now.
Application
You can see that storage has a value called in28minutes.
So we are able to authenticate.
We are able to set it into the session, and in the next steps we will use this information. We use this
method to do a lot more stuff around the login.
I'll see you in the next Video. Until then, Bye!