Welcome back. In the previous step, we looked at a few ng commands: ng lint,  ng build, ng test
and ng e2e.
We looked at a few files which are related to each of those commands.
When we look at our folder structure, there are still files which we have not really talked about. In
this video,
let's try and cover the other folders which are present in our workspace.
When they open up the source folder, you'd see something called app.
This is where all our angular code would go into.  When we build angular app, we would create them using something
called components and modules. All the components and modules will be present in this app folder.
The assets folder is where all the images go into. The content which needs to be rendered as it is, like images.
They all go into the assets.
folder. When we develop applications, we would want to deploy them in multiple
environments,  dev environment,  QA, production, test.
All the configuration for each of these environments go into the environment folder. Now that we looked
at the important folders,
let's look at the other files which are present in here.
Let's start with the configjJson. Know that we'd be writing code in typescript.
But do you know that your browser will not understand it, as your browser only understands javascript
So whatever code that we write it needs to be converted to javascript, or whatever typescript code that
we write as part of our source code needs to be converted to typescript. That is specified as part of
the config.json.
We already looked at README.md, which is kind of the documentation for this project.
So if you have something to document about the project , you can put it in the meat or empty your building
angular application.
And we saw a number of commands which you were able to execute in the last step.
ng lint, ng build, ng test and ng e2e.
And all these things need a lot of external frameworks and tools. All these frameworks and tools are
specified in the package.json
file. So on you'd see that all the frameworks are specified in here, are packages are specified in her
, as well as all the tools that we would need to be able to run the unit tests,  integration testsm, and to run
our angular application, whatever models you have defined in package.json.
I downloaded. When you run NPM install, node package manager is the package manager we're using.
It's very similar to Maven.
So once you specify the dependencies in here, when we do npm install, all these dependencies downloaded
to the node_modules folder. The node_modules is where all your packages.
That's basically your frameworks, and also the tools that you'd need to build and run your project.
are downloaded to.
We did not really explicitly do npm install at all.
When we create a new angular app using ng new, the npm install command is automatically executed.
The .gitignore file contains what are the different folders which should not be committed to version
control.
So when you commit this project version control, all these folders would be ignored.
Index.html which you see in here and the main.html, is inside the src folder now, so  main.ts
and
the index.html which is present in here, are the things which are loaded up when we launch the
angular application.
So these are responsible for bootstrapping the angular application at the high level.
That is something called the root module which will be launched up by the browser.
Which will be included in index.html, and that's how the application get bootstrapped.
We'll look at bootstrapping in Angular a little later.
The other files which I present in here is something called polyfills.
Yes we know that different browsers have different levels of support for all the web standards. The
same javascript code might not work in all the browsers.
Files like this would take care of these browser incompatibilities and make sure that whatever code
that we write would be compatible with all the browsers.
The styles.css is very you specified the global application styles.
So whatever styles.
whatever CSS you would want to use across the application, you'd put it inside the styles.css
That
is what is basically the starting point for running the units.
So this is what is used when we run the ng test. In this video, we saw that all the other files which we
were not able to cover inside of the previous step.
The important one which we discussed were package.json, where we define all the tools and frameworks
that we make use of.
And these are downloaded to our node_models folder, when we run and do an install. The npm install is run automatically.
for us, when we were creating the new project. The tsconfig.json defines how we would want
to convert the typescript code we would write, to javascript code which runs on the browser.
The app contains all the important code, typically model components and all the other stuff that you
would write as part of you angular applications, as it contains things like images that you would want
to use. And it might contain environment specific configuration if you want.
Dev-specific configuration, or production specific configuration,  that's what goes into environment
polyfills ensure that all the code that you write is compatible across all liberals.
styles.css contains the global styles,  globalCSS. And test.ts  is a starting point for running
unit tests.
The idea behind the last two steps is to give you 10000 feet view on the project structure: the different
folders, different files which are present in here.
It's not really necessary that you need to know the absolute details of everything which is present
in here.
It's efficient if you know at a high level.
This is related to this, and that would help you
when we start building the app. I'll see you in the next step.
Until then, Bye-bye.