Welcome back. In the previous step, we stored the  user on  authentication into session storage, and we created
a method to check for users logged in or not. What we have also done is we made a couple of logs.
It's not really good, so let's comment these out, so that the logs don't disturb us.
We make sure that everything is working fine, so the logs are not really needed anymore.
Now what do you want to do?
You would want to enable and disable menu items.
Based on is user logged in or not.
So I want to enable these links based on user logging in.
How can I do that?
Think about it. If user has logged in, I would want to show different links if a user is not logged in,
I would want to show different things to be done here.
And think about it, before you would proceed to look at the solution.
What we have in here is the menu component. menu component defined so  menu.component.html.
HTML
So before we show these links, I would need to check if user logged in or not.
How can I do that?
Think about it.
It should be easy right?
So let's go to another component.
And first add in our authentication service. We need to check whether somebody is logged in are not.
We need the authentication service right?
So let's inject it in and say private authentication hardcoded authentication service.
Actually I'll copy this again and paste it here, and take :. with them.
Let's make it small h.
So we have the hardcodedAuthenticationService very long!
Now what we want to do is on the initialization of this component, will want to check hardcoded authentication
service. For this, you need to say this.hardcodedAuthenticationService
What we would want to find out, what you want to find out.
is the user logged in?
We need to find out if this user has logged in, and let's put this into a variable isUserLoggedIn.
And this would be a boolean, and let's initialize it to false.
And if user is logged in then I would initialize.
What's the error? this.
this.isUserLoggedIn = ...
So now I can do this component property in the view.
So let's go to the menu.component.html, and over here I can say display this, only og user has
logged in. How can I say that?
Think about it, how can I say that?
use ngIf..
If it's equal to ...... so show this only if user is logged in. is logged in ... show this if show only if you
just logged in ... log out.
Show it if user is logged in and log in.
show it if user has not logged in.
Right.
I'm putting a not in here.
Isn't that interesting.
Let's see what would happen. if we refresh page if you see it now three links are shown: home, todos
and log out.
That's cool right!
We are able to see all these three links.
Let's remove this.
Let's clear this out and let's go back to the homepage. you would see that these three links remain here.
So even though it's not they're in session storage, it's still visible. what's happening?
Why are we able to see the links, even though I have deleted this from station storage?
The reason is because this menu component is initialized only once.
Right at the end of the page.
So once we leave the page we're not refreshing the content of this menu component, so ngOnInit()
will not be called.
So whatever value was initially stored that remained as it is.
So if I completely refresh the page, so I'm not just clicking the link but I'm refreshing the page you'd
see that the links would go away.
So you would see that login is the only one which is shown because, in session storage the user name
is not there.
So you login.
Sure.
And even if now in28minutes, dummy and I login, I would see that only login menu item is shown. Remeaning
are not shown because even though the item is there in the session.
So if you refresh the session storage, you'd see that the item is there, but it's not picked up by the menu
because the menu is not being refreshed at all.
The ngOnInit() on the menu component gets called only when the page gets refreshed.
And the way we can avoid this is by calling the service. So we can go into the menu and the stuff thing
we would say this
now let's see what would happen if
menu gets refreshed.
And you would see that you see the links, and when you delete this clear and when you go back to the
page immediately, you only see the login page because it's thinking that there is nothing in the section.
So the user has logged out.
One of the things you would have observed upto now, is even though it is logged out, we are still showing it on the
page.
We are still showing the welcome page and things like that.
That's something which we would fix very soon.
But the important thing for us is to make sure, that the menu items are displayed according to whether
the user is logged in or not.
And that's what we were able to accomplish in this specific step.
One of the things I will do, is I'll quickly comment out the stuff which we did in here, which is not
being used at all.
This specific thing in here is not being used.
These two things are not, so I'll just comment it out.
So it's there for your future reference. In this step, we enabled the menu items.
We enable the top menu items based on what our users log in or not.
One of the important things we keep doing throughout this course, is if we make mistakes that's the only
way we can improvise things.
Once you make a mistake and learn from it, you'll never do it again.
And that's the best way to learn.
And that's exactly what we keep doing.
I'll see you in the next step . Bye!