Welcome back.
As of now in the application, when you log in and enter a password to log in, this particular thing it created
in sessions storage. However, the only way we are removing this stuff out is by doing a right-click
remove.
We should actually implement that functionality.
We should implement it as part of our logic.
Let's quickly do that in this specific step.
We'll start off creating the logout component.
Be very careful.
We are not creating a service.
What we are creating is a component.
Actually we are going to create a logout component. So ng generate component logout... go out and do that
and that's cool.
So logout is done.
If you click logout right now will it work.
Nope not yet.
Not so fast.
Why?
Because you've not done the routing right.
So let's add the routing.
As usual, ** should be the last one.
Do not make the mistake of adding something after **.
logout: and it should be logout component and refresh.
/ out
Logout works.!
That's cool.
So now logout pages is there
Now logout.component.html
We'll put a h1, You Are Logged Out.
And put a div,  class =container
and just put a simple message out saying thank you.
For using
our application. cool, you are logged out.
Thank you for using our application.
That's good, but is it all? What we want to do is actually go out to the logout.component.ts, and make
sure that the user is logged out.
Now let's go to the hardcoded authentication service.
We don't really have anything to log out our user, right? So what we do is create a new method
logout()
and all that we need to do is say sessionStorage.removeItem()
authenticatedUser.
So what we are doing here, is we are removing the authenticated user from session storage and this particular
thing hardcoded authentication service.
You need to use it in the logout component.
How can we use that?
We need to inject it in a the component.
I'll make it hard coded authentication so use it.
Import this in, as we put it in ngOnInit().
What do we need to do, when the component is initialized?
To say this.hardcodedAuthenticationService.logout() . what would happen?
The logout method would be called, and we would be logged out.
Let's see what would happen if it we refresh.
You'd see that you are logged out, and that's removed in sessionStorage..
If the value is there, you can see that the value is not there.
This is basically the search thing, and you can see that it's not there.
Do it again.
So give dummy log in, and you can see ... let's refresh it...  you can see that in28minutes with its values there.
And as soon as I click logout, you can also see the menus react.
So the menus don't appear. So we'll leave the log in menus here right now and you can see when you refresh
it.
It's also not showing the value in the session storage.
Isn't this fun!
So now we have a proper implementation of a logout and login. So you can see you are logged out... When
you log in, and save dummy as the password and log in,
You can go there play with it, and log out.
This is awesome right!
So this is much more clear application. You have login and  logout features, and all that working perfectly.
The only thing which I don't really like about what's happening in here, is the fact that if I type in
localhost:4200/todos, I'm still able to do the see the todos, even though I'm not logged in, and that's
not really good right!
I would want to be able to see that todo only when I'm logged in.
Let's get to that in the next step.
Bye Bye!