Welcome back.
One of the things which we are seeing right now, is the fact that when I directly entered the URL, I would still
get the details, even though I'm not really logged in.
And that's not really good.
That's not accurate.
I like to make the application secure, by actually trying to authenticate before we allow user to go
to specific URL.
A quick word of caution. if you're hearing a few crackers in the background it's because it's Diwali time
in India right now.
If there are few crackers sound in the background that you're hearing that's because it's Diwali in
India.
Wish me Happy Diwali as well.
OK let's get to the task at hand.
So that is where we have defined the route, in the app-routing.model.ts . What we want to do is
before executing the route, we would want to check something out.
You'd want to check if the user is logged in, before he can go to the welcome page, that he's actually
been loggen before he goes to this page.  Whether he's equal whether his logged in before he goes to the todos
page.
So how do we do that?
What you are looking at right now is app routing module.
This is where we find our routes. Over here we can specify conditions when these can be activated.
So I can say activate this specific condition, activate this only in specific condition.
What we'll do is we will activate welcome.component, list-todos component, and logout  component, only when
a user is logged in.
But to be able to do that, we need to implement the service and tie it up down here.
So this is called a RouteGuardService.
RouteGuardService.
You would want to call it.
So what do we do, is
We'll start creating this service.
I want to create a service.
The service I would want to create, again in this service folder itself and I'll call this service/
routeguard
Be very careful.
You don't need to specify the service at the end.
So it's ng generate service service/routeGuard
Then open up the routeguardservice.
ts.
And before we can implement logic in the service,  is one important thing is, this needs to implement a
specific interface, before I can use it in the router.
The interface is called CanActivate
The important thing to note is there are multiple imports that match this CanActivate, so be careful and
choose the one which is from the angular router package. So you can see it in here or to input from @angular
/route
So the one which we need to import is from the router package. so you can see now over here, CanActivate
from @angular/router.
Now you can see that it says an error.
It says it incorrectly implements the interface CanActivate it as property can activate is missing.
What does that mean?
This means that we have not really implemented the method which is defined in the CanActivate.
So what I'll do is I'll make it easy.. So I'll go here and copy the method thing , and do a control click.
You can go to that.
I'll copy the method definition. What it's saying,
It should either it in an observable, or a promise, of a boolean. to really worry about it.
Fair enough.
Let's remove all that stuff and let's put these in.
Let's start with the activated route.
Snapshot control space and put it in. Next, RouterStateSnapshot and import it as well.
So you can see that all these are from the same package.
So if you don't get this suggestion, then make sure that you add this import.
They are all from angular/router.
The error is because we are not returning anything back.
It's true.
Just to make the whole thing happy.
Now what do you want to do in here.
What do you want to do is we would want to return true, only if the user is logged in.A certain links.
We only want to enable when a user is logged in.
And in those kind of situations only, we would want to return true back.
So how can we implement that?
Think about it.
You'd want it to only when the user is logged in. how can I find out if the user is logged in? Hardcoded
authentication service.
Again HardcodedAuthenticationService private
h,  and let's control space... implement ... import it in if HardcodedAuthenticationService. import it in
return true.
Else return false.
What would happen if we leave... a user has logged in then it would return true.
Otherwise it would return false.
What I can do is use this in... let's quickly format this... right click format document so the code is formatted.
What we'll do in the next step is to make use of this code.  In this step,
What we did is we implemented a quick logout service in the router for each of the links. Before we
go to that specific thing.
We want to check if user is actually logged in, before we can see the truth or we continue to the.
Welcome page.
And that's what the RouteGuardService enables us to do.
We just need a to implement CanActivate interface, and it defines a specific method based on the activated route
and the route snapshot.
We don't really need to use any of that information. What  we need to do is use the authentication service,
to check if user is logged in. If user loggend in, return true. Else,  false.
Let's make use of this  in the next video.
Bye Bye!