Welcome back. In the previous step, we implemented the RouteGuardService.
Let's use it.
In this step. A lot of it is actually very very easy.
All you need to do is go to the routing module,  and add attribute called canActivate. Where you want to add this
over here canActivate, and say call and say : this. canActivate can accept an array.
So you need to put this within an array []. So this can actually have multiple Guard services. You can find multiple
guards. That facility which is provided in here and these guards are executed one after the other.
So now what we want to do is, this can be activated only when the routeguard service returns true.
Let's check this out.
One of the things you can make sure, is to make sure that you replace the entire page.
Again I had a few problems with that.
routeguardservice... then and was automatically picking up the change.
But when I completely refreshed it, It stopped having problems.
Make sure to refresh the page or wait for a little while.
If you have any problems, you need to type in the username and password and click logging.
Now we are logged in.
So we be able to go to todos right.
localhost:4200/todos.
That works... /welcome in28minutes.
That works.
Now let's logout.
So the user is logged out, but we are trying to access todos. Will this work?
No it doesn't work.
You are getting an empty page.
That's good.
So your routeguard is in action.
If you have any problems with routeguard,  what I would recommend you to do is to try and print something
so try and log something into your console, and see if it's getting called or not.
So just before this, just put a log and check whether your  target is getting fired at all.
If it's not then, check whether you have a property at it in the specific code.
I hope so. When I say it is it showing an empty page.
It's not really taking me to the log in page.
Ideally when I type in invalid URL, not something ...I would really love it if the page if the application
automatically takes me back to the login page.
Right! Then I can go in and log in details, and again check if everything is fine.
So let's do that right now.
RouteGuardsService, as we said, if this.hardcodedAuthenticationService.isUserLoggedIn() return true... else
we are returning false.
What I would need to do is, I would want to allow the user to the log in page.
How can I do that?
Think about it how can I do that? The way I can do that is by adding on the by injecting one of the parameters.
What do we need?
We need the router.
Right!
Public or private router...
So I'm going to take the router
and over here's what we need to
router. oops.. this.router.navigate
Which page do you want to go to?
So if I say /todos,  I'm not logged in, so I'm send back to the login page. dummy log in.
You now I can go and look at my todos. In this specific step,
We took the routeguard which was implemented in the previous step, and we tied it up with the menu items and
now we see that we have a cool looking app.
We see that logout, login and everything works fine.
We're able to click the links in the menu.
We are able to logout, and once you are logged out, you would see that the welcome screen does not work
anymore.
It will take you to the log in page.
The same is the case with the todos screen.
This is a nice application that we have built over the last few steps.
And this is the first time this looks like a real world application. It might not be really perfect yet,
because there a lot of stuff is hardcoded.
I know that, but still you deserve a pat on your back.
So time to celebrate go have a party and come back and I'll see you in the next step. Bye Bye!