Welcome back.
Let's do a quick review of what we have done and set up the stage for the next section.
The most important though is that we have created in the last few steps is the hardcoded authentication
service. This hardcoded authentication service is having the features to authenticate for now,  users with
hard coding, and when it is authenticated it puts the user details into session storage.
And it also has a method to enable us to check if a user is logged in, or if a user wants to log out.
So this is complete authentication.
So this authentication service is made use of by the logon and the logout component, as well as the menu
component.
You can see that this is used across multiple components.
And how are we providing the service to those components.
We are using dependency injection. As soon as you put this annotation @injectable and provided in
the scope in any class.
It's available for dependency injection, and whenever it is needed, all that you need to do is you need
to inject it in in the constructor.
So what we did in here is we injected this into the constructors. So it becomes constructor we added
in a parameter and that's it, we're here!
I can start using the hardcoded authentication service
Injection is an awesome feature in Angular, and implementing dependency injection is really really easy.
The other thing which we implemented was the router guard servies. we implemented an interface it
CanActivate
We had to define a method called canActivate.
And what we did is: we check if a user is logged in. If the user has logged in, return true, and false if the user is not
really logged in.
What we did is we navigate to the login page.
So for menu items which need a logged user, we placed this guard in front of the menu route.
So in the routing model for all the links, all the route which need a logged in user, We activated the
router guard service.
So this would make sure that only logged in users would be able to reach these parts.
One of the things you would have already observed, is the fact that and that makes it very very easy
to develop front end applications.
A lot of features are built into the framework, and its all about making the right use of those features.
What will we be doing in the next few steps.
We will switch our attention to building the backend. We'll start building a service in the back end
using spring boot.
We would start with writing a little bit of hard coded business logic, to get some data out.
we'll try and connect the front end in angular,
and the back-end in springboot.
That's what we will be doing over the next few steps.
I'm excited to bring all this to you and I'll see you in the next step.
Until then, bye bye!