Welcome back.
Let's get introduced to one of the most important concepts in Angular, which is called component.
Let's consider that we want to develop a page like this.
We have a menu at the top, and we have a list of todo's which are shown and we have footer. In Angular, the
way we would develop
this, is as a set of components.
So the page would be divided into a number of components.
So we would have a menu component.
We would have a list of todo components.
We would have a footer component.
Each of these components are responsible for displaying the view, that's basically the html,  the styling.
That's basically the CSS, as well as the code to react to the user actions.
So when user clicks update, when user clicks delete, when you add todo, what needs to be done?
All that is handled by the view logic which is present in that specific component.
This menu component is responsible for showing the list of menu items: which is highlighted, which is
not highlighting, the styling for that, and handling the click of the event.
If home is clicked, if it's clicked or log out is clicked. When we build Angular applications, we first
start thinking about what should be the component which should be created.
Typically a component is associated with a template which is basically the HTML.
How should it be shown, the styling, which is basically this.
Is this how should the elements be styled ,and the code: how should you really respond to use of actions.
This is written in typescript.
When we look at most components in Angular, you would see that the template file is having extension of
dot component, and the style file has a .component.css extension and the code file has a component.ts
The extension .ts stands for typescript.
When you look at our workspace, that is one component which is already present in here.
It's called the app component, and you would see that the extensions exactly match to what we have seen
earlier.
So we have a html template: component.html.
That's basically the app.component.html.
We have the styling in app.component.css.
This file is empty for now.
And we have the code which is pleasant in app.component.ts. In Angular would indicate that
something is a component by using something called a decorator.
The decorator is very similar to annotations in Java.
We use the decorator at component to indicate that the app component is a component, and we have a few
attributes which are specified as part of the component decorator.
The first one is the selector, it is basically the tag name for this component.
So if I want to make use of this component, what tag name should I use as the selector.
So if you look at index.html, which is where this particular component is used it is app root.
The next thing which is present in here is something called app.component.html, which
is the template you want.
So what we are saying is where is the location of the HTML template for this specific component, and we
said it's in the app.component.html.
The other thing which we specify in here is where is the styling for that specific component.
So the cpp.component.css is where typically the styling which is specific to this specific
component is present.
You can see that as part of our component code, we have some data we have a member available to represent
in here this member variable is actually mapped to this value in here.
What we're using in here is something called interpolation.
So what it does is it takes the value which is present in here and put it in here.
So let's say I would want to create on that one.
So let's say I'm saying message = "welcome
to In28minutes".  what I can do in here is I can use interpolation and I can put
within curly brackets or braces, I can put in the message. you would see when you look at the page.
You would see "welcome to IN 28 minutes".
Also as part of your .  What are we doing in here
is called binding.
You're taking some data from the component and showing it in the view.
In this quick step we looked at the component.
We said all Angular applications are built up of a number of components.
Each component has the HTML or the template, the styling or CSS, and code to handle the view actions.
This code is written in typescript, but it's because the fact that a component decorator is what makes
this app component a component. We look at the attributes which are part of the @component decorator, the templateUrl
and the styleUrl, as well as the tag which is used to to present this element.
And we looked at the fact that, what we did is present as part of the component we can use it in the
template by using interpolation.
I leave you with an exercise.
What I would recommend you to do is create a few more data elements as part of this, and make sure that
you use them in your app.component which do you plan on with it.
I'll see you.