In the previous video, we looked at the basics of component. In this video, let's play around with the app component
a little bit more.
I'll start with going to the app.component.ts, and over here what I'll do is I would want to directly
include the entire template in here, instead of actually putting the UI to where the HTML present.
You can also include the exact template. Later I would want to show that one,. For now,  let's start with
just putting the title in.
(I'm using CAPS LOCK!!).
Let's do that.
Let's make this one.
And this should be
What would happen?
If I go and refresh the page, it says this module cannot be found.
What it's saying is I'm not able to locate the template you are in.
The thing is I need to change the attribute to template.
So if you say its template then you can directly define the template in here.
So you can see that now, todo is display to the page because that's the only thing which is present
in the template.
What I'll do is undo the change.
Let's go back to where we were earlier.
Comment this out and paste this in.
So what we're doing is we are replacing the template URL. Instead of the templateURL< you'rw
using template and thereby we can actually put the complete code of the component right here, if you'd
want.
You can do something like that with the style as well.
What we'll do, is we'll comment this out and let's continue using that template because we would want to
see a lot of code.
Now if you go to the template, you are able to... what we'll do in here is create additional div. Let's create a
div Component Content,  and what we'll do with index.html...
Let's go here,
And also we're here let's create a div So this div is actually index.html content
to be created.
There's one in the index.html,  one in the app.component.ts.
If you look at the screen right now, you'd see the content in here.
So the content is displayed as part of the index.html.
Now let's style the divs
So I say give background-color just make it
beige.
You can see that just the component alone get the background color, because the content in the index.html
does not get the style.
So what do you put in here,
does not apply to all the div's which are present in here.
What you put in app.component.
always only applies to the continent.
The scope of the style that you are specifying in here is restricted to the component and that's awesome.
Let's comment it out
The appearance does not really look good.
So let's comment this out. The way I'm doing it is Control-/ or command-/.
If you do that it gets commented out. Now,  you would be back to the usual stuff. In this quick video,
We tried to play around with the component. We tried to create a template directly in here, by using the
template properties.
And we tried to create a simple style inside the app.component.ts, and we were able to see that the
style was affecting only the specific component.
I would recommend you to try and play around with the template and the templateUrl, and try
and understand it more as an exercise.
I'll see you in the next step.