Welcome back. In the step, let's focus on understanding the syntax of the typescript that we see.
We will look at this in-depth, we will identify which part are coming from javascript, and which are added in
by typescript.
And how do they compare against your Java code! What I have done is taken up the WelcomeComponent so
the Welcome Component I have added in Java code,  in comments.
So each line of commented code that you'll see in here is a piece of Java code. As you would know in
Java, we would write classes and group them into packages.
So at the top of every Java class, you would see something called package. Or, if you don't put up an
package declaration, it becomes part of the default package. In javascript,
we write classes, and all the classes in a single file are considered to be part of a module.
You'll find we only have one class, but the thing is you can create other classes as well. So I can say export
class Class1, and also create a number of classes in here.
This combined thing is called a module. A module in javascript represents one file which contains
class and function definitions.
So if you don't remember it, it's one file per module, and one module per file, and modules is how you would
organize classes in Javascript.
Now let's say I would want to use a class from another module. The way you do that in Javascript is by
using an import statement here.
This is a built in Angular package.
Let's say I would want to use AppComponent, so I would want to use.
Let's go to the loader.
So let's I would want to use the AppComponent.
This class in here.
This AppComponent which is present in here.
How can I do that? The way I can do that is by saying import component from you need to say the path
to that particular module. You'll find it is that the model for the path ../
So I'm going to the root,
Now I'm here in app. In ../app.component. and you don't need to specify the
.ts.
So this is how you would specify it, and you would put this at this.
So if I want to use the AppComponent,  this is how you would import it in. Because it's not used in the code
of the specific class, it's highlighted in a kind of like the shade.
This is how you would import a class which is defined in one of the more or one of the files, which is
present inside out own package.
The concept of modules as we see in here was introduced in javascript.
ES
6.
Now let's move on to the definition of a class. The definition of a class is very similar to how we do
it in Java. class and class name, making the class implement the interface, implements on and it is more
of a typescript feature, and this is exactly the same as how we would do that in Java.
The important difference comes,
when you would want to use this class outside this module, or outside this particular file in Java
one of the options which is present is public.
So if I want to use a class outside the package, I can make it public and it can be used everywhere else
in Javascript, the option you need to use something called export. export here indicates that I would
want to use this class outside the boundary of this particular module, outside the boundary of this particular
file.
So if I do a control-X,  and remove the import and saving it, you would see that we would have a few compilation
errors.
If I open up the app, that is what you'd see is: a compilation error.
I cannot use a WelcomeComponent, because it is not exported.
So if you want to use a class outside the boundary of it's module, you would need to explore it.
So the concept is very simple: If you want to use a class from outside the module, you would have to import
it. If you'd want to expose a class outside the boundary of this model,
Then you need to export it.
Now let's shift our attention to the way we define a constructor. It is by using a keyword called constructor
in Java, would have done something like this: we would have said public class name and typical method
syntax.
Now moving on to the normal method.
Typically if it was Java, then you would do something like this wide in it or something like that. In
Javascript, you don't really need to worry about the return type,  because you cannot declare it. Typescript
It makes it safer,
And in typescript you can say :void.
This says this particular method will not return anything back. If it if you would want to return a string,
You can put string in here.
So if you see code anywhere in your colon and declaring it type, then it's basically the return type.
Now let's move on to member variables.
Let's say I would want declared a variable in here.
The way I can do that in Javascript would be to say OK message = ... and some welcome message.
and I can use this in say the method, by saying this.message. so I can say console.log(
message).
If I did the same thing in Java, it would have looked something like String message =  ...  I have
to use double quote in Java for strings, right.
So that's basically the way you would do it in Javascript. in Javascript, you don't really need to worry
about the single quote or double quote, both of them would work.
Typically I prefer using single quote
So I do this kind of stuff.
This is how you do it in Javascript, in typescript.
You can also add a type. so you can do message.
:string =  ...
So if you see code of this type, and then it says message is a string.
And I would want to have this default value for it.
The thing is typescript is intelligent.
So even if you remove this, it knows that message is a string value.
So if I say a message = 5 in here, it would start complaining.
Actually I should say this.message,  and I just said message.
If I said this, this is what messages go to.
Then  I could assign 5 to it.
It's a string type.
So typescript is intelligent.
It knows the value assigned to it.
What is the type of it?
And it can recognize that.
So this would give us a compilation error.
The last thing we would want to look at is the decorator.
So what do you see in here.
A decorator! In Java, you would call it annotation, you would have annotation and different attributes
similar to that in typescript.
This is called a decorator. In a decorator, we are passing an object, so over here, we apply it in object and
we are setting the attributes of that. It's just similar to how we would do attribute in Java.
OK we have discussed a lot of things in this specific video.
The idea is to give you a quick overview of how things are different between typescript and Java.
So we started talking about the fact that in Java we use packages to organize classes, whereas in javascript
all the classes which are present in a single file and all the other functions which happens in here
are part of a module.
And if you want to use class from external module,  you'd need to import it in if you want to.
allow usage of this class outside this specific module.
You need to export it a little bit.
The syntax of classes, constructors, methods and member variables.
As I said before this is just to give you a quick overview.
We did not really cover every nook and corner as we go along.
You learn more about javascript and typescript.
I like you to watch the lecture again and focus on every word of it.
Being comfortable with the syntax is very important.
Make a backup of the class, remove each word from it, and see what happens.
Good luck, and I'll see you.