Welcome back.
Let's shift our attention to enhancing the application which you want to create.
We created an welcome page, and now let's look forward to creating a login page, what will the login page typically contain?
a user name and a password.
Let's create a simple page with a user name and password, and we use a LoginComponent to contain all
the code of that.
How do you create a component? And let's use the ng, and ng generate. What do we want to generate?
We want to generate a component. What is the name of it?
Login. This is very very simple.
It's something that you'd would be doing a number of times, during the specific course, and actually you'd
be doing this a number of times during your career,  because you would want to create a lot of components
when you are writing Angular code.
Let's go ahead and do that, Login.
It would create. How many files would it create? It creates four files, and it updates the app.module.
What does that mean here?
This login component is created.
And the login component is added to the app module, and the login component...
How many files are created for us?
A CSS file, a HTML file, and the typescript file, which would contain the view logic too. This would
contain the styling, this would contain the view, and this would contain the view logic.
This file... we'll not worry about this... it would be typically be the unit test file.
Let's open up the IDE, and you would see login here and this is where the whole thing is.
And the easiest way to open up files is by just pressing control-P or command-P.
Let's start using control-P and command-P be to start opening the files, because that would help you remember
the names of the files.
better. So log.component.ts , css, html
These are the 3 important files. Let's go to the HTML file.
It says login works right now.
Let's see the application, login works
is not really shown. why?
Because we are not including
The login tag anywhere.
What is the tag of the logging component?
Let's go to login.component.ts.
Yes.
The tag is app-login.
So let's open up which file would contain code for including the tag in? It would be the component, because
that's kind of the component where we are generating, we are driving everything from.
So I can open and start off.
And from there we are including all the other components.
So if I want to show the login page, I can say  here.
Right let's see if I see the content.
Yep it says logging works right now.
So now you can see login work as part of this particular thing as well.
One of the important things is the fact that right now, we are including all the components as part
of the root component, which is the app component.
So what is happening here, is the root component is getting loaded, which is the app component, and the
root component contains a number of other components.
So all the other components are getting in there.
That's part of the component.
What we want to do from here on, is just focus on a specific component it.
So what I'll do,  is this code
This is not really needed anymore, and I'll comment out the app.
"welcome", and all the content below.
We don't really need it anymore.
What we'll do is we'll start focusing on the login, and at a later point in time we would make use of
router.
So the router would help us to bring from logging to welcome page, and all that fun stuff.
Let's not really worry about it right now. Let's focus on the login page.
And if you go to the browser, the only thing you are seeing right now is login works. Index HTML
And where is this coming from?
This is coming from the index file.
So in the index.html file, we are loading the root component and the root component.
After that we have this.
So let's come in this out as well.
The shortcut if you'd want to comment something out, is control-/ or command-/.
It would comment anything, whether it's HTML, whether it's Javascript, you can easily comment it.
Now let's go to the page, and you'll see that "login works" is the only one which we are seeing now.
Let's focus on the login component. login that component data is where it's present.
Let's create a simple login page.
So I would want to get the username and the password. How do we get the name and password? Typically in
which HTML would create an input element. So <input type="text"... and you would want to say, we would want to
put in the name, and the name is user.name. And let's have a password, for the last one <input type=
"password".
And name it user.password as well.
Right now if you go to the browser, you would see a username and password.
This looks like a typical page. Now styling it. We talk about styling a little later, for now what we
have is very basic page, which is the username and password. And I can enter some values in here and we can do
nothing with it right now.
OK.
In this video, we created the login component, and cleaned everything up so that the only thing that
we are seeing on the screen is the login component. In the next step,
Let's make the login component a little bit more functional.
I'll see you in the next step. Until then, bye-bye!