Welcome back. In the previous step, we created a simple login component, and we said in this step, we'll
add a little bit more complexity to it.
Let's get started.
In this specific step. Now we have a user name and password. That looks good but we don't really have
a button yet.
Right!
Typically you need a button to be able to log in.
So let's add a button.  and lets call it a login button.
Will I be able to see the login button?
Yes I can see the log in button, and click the logging button.
Nothing is happening in here! So I can enter the username and password and I can click log in.
Nothing is happening in here, right! When I do, I click to inspect, and go to the console,
You don't see anything down here yet.
What can I do to make sure, that I can perform an action when the logon button is clicked?
Typically, when you write typical javascript, what we do is we created,  we create a javascript file (external one) and
we create a method in it, and we will stay onclick.
= doSomething, and it takes a very very simple approach.
We made use of something called data binding.
So let's open up the login component.. login.component,
Yes that's the one that you would want to open.
What are we going do.
Well here we can have a... let's say a default value for the user, and I take that username =
the default value.
I would want to give this, let's say,
in28minutes
(All small).
Be careful with it.
So your name is in28minutes attached to the default user name that I would want to show, and the default
password I would want to show is password = ''.
Let's use single quotes to keep it consistent.
So we have a user name in28minute, password is empty.
Now I would want to share this default on the login code.
How can we do that.
Think about it, we used this feature a little while ago.
We can do that, is by saying value =  what the value should be?
We can use interpolation. We can do interpolation, to get the value which is in the component.
So from the component, I want to get the value for what for use that name.
So let's go ahead and do that.
Now it says value = username, and password the default value would be empty.
Let's receive it.
Let's put password in here, that's the name username and password.
We are taking these names, and we are putting them in here.
Let's see what would happen.
Then the page refreshes by default. user name has in28minutes
So what we're doing in here, is we are taking data from the component and tying it to the template.
So from the view logic where the data is present, we are tying it down to a template for starting off.
Let's say when logging button is clicked,  I would want to print the user name. The way we can do that in
Angular is by doing something called event binding.
So the syntax of the binding is nothing but event. Which event are you listening to?
And method do you want to call?
So what should you do?
So when are you going to have event, what should you do?
The event we are looking for here is something called click.
So we're looking for the click event, and what we want to do is we would want to call a method. What
is the method that I would want to call to handle login?
Let's refresh the page and click login, but nothing happened.
Inspect control it says handleLogin() is not really a function.
How do we fix this?
We said call handleLogin(), but we did not really define the handleLogin any way.
The great thing about Angular is the fact that the place where we would be this is the login component
So this component would handle all the view logic.
So all the methods which are related to the view, would be coded in login component. So what I need
to do, is define a method called handleLogin() in here, and let's do a simple control.log.
Let's just print. well certainly, can see that there is a compilation error because when you are referring
to member variables, you have to use this log. Let's see what would happen now when you say login
it's printing in28minutes.
That's a small warning in here, which you can ignore if you are really interested, and just go and read
about it.
That's what would happen if I change the user name in28minutes, change it and click logging it again
it's printing in28minutes
The log here says that in28minutes is printed earlier, and again right now.
So I get that in28minutesExtended, but it's printing in28minutes.
again. How do I take the data from the login element from the view element, and populate it into the component
data?
What we are able to do is take the component data,
We were able to use interpolation, and put it on the screen. But now what we want to do, is what the user
has typed in,
I would want to be able to take it and show it in the component.
How do I do that?
Think about it and I'll see you in the next step.