Welcome back.
We created a few services using spring boot the last few steps.
And when I ran this Hello World application,  I get this message back.
Now the interesting part is how do you call these services
from your front-end, and from our application.
What we'll start with is we take the welcome screen, and we add a button in here so let's add a button
in here. And our eventual aim is to be able to call the service and see the message which is coming back
in here. The next few steps would help you understand the complexities associated with invoking RESTful
API from angular applications.
We will use something called HTTPClientModule, where you'll see that Angular provides us with an awesome
framework based on something called the observable.
But let's get started now.
Let's start with enhancing the welcome screen to have a button, and something which we can click. Before
we get started,
Make sure that you are able to run the REST service, as well as you have your Angular thing up and
running.
Or you go to our favorite IDE. visual studio code, and let's move on to welcome.component.
ts. similar to what we would want to add.
So let's copy this out.
I'll copy this, and create a todo. What I'll do is allow a simple message in here: click here.
to get customized welcome page. and let's have a simple button in here right... button.
And what do you want to do?
We would want to enable the click event, to click. So we are doing and event binding.
So we would want to bind to a specific method, and just call this get welcome message.
We create this method. let's create this method. I call this:  get welcome.
cool! If you would go to the screen, you would see that it would refresh and you have the get welcome
a message.
Let's add a simple class .button.
The bootstrap... and we would want to set this button.
Success.
It doesn't reflect! It's time for me to relearn my CSS... thinks I should not really have a dot in here.
So the message at the place here.
Now to get welcome message ...button appears in the form we would want.
What you want to do is click on this button right.
If I click this button right now what would happen.
You know what would happen.
It would give us an error.
Obviously right! To go to the console, you would see that there's an error.
There is no method of that kind present.
So getwelcomemessage() is not a function so we should recreate this function.
Think about it.
Where should I create the getwelcomemessage function?
The component is welcome.
Component.ts is where we would go.
And let's quickly create that function.  getwelcomemessage() is the method that would be
invoked when ... console.log() getwelcomemessage().
Cool.
When I say get welcome message
Get welcome message is printed out to the console. let's comment out the other message which is coming
in here.
The console.log() which you wrote in an earlier step.
So the only thing which we see right now is what we get from here.
That's good.
Now we have a button, we have tied it to a method inside the welcome component. But what we really want
to do is we would want to invoke this hello world.
That's the thing that we would want to do.
How do we invoke the service?
As usual we create a new service.
This service would call up backend service a backend API.
That's the reason why we call it data service, and getting what you get is the welcome message.
Let's go back to our favorite Angular CLI.
Make sure that you are inside the folder.
You can see if I open the present working directory in the root folder of the Angular application.
That's cool.
I want to generate a service. ng generate service... and I want to have a service...
So what I do is I create it in folder structures service/data.
So this is where we have all the services.
Lets group all the data. So we sit in the data folder and what data does it get ?So the data it would get
is welcomeData
So I'm saying service/data/welcomeData
So we had to create a data service in the folder.
So with /data to what would have been PRESS ENTER It would create a couple of files as usual.
And it's welcomeData service.
Let's take the welcome data service to pick up the welcome data.
These file and over here, you can see that it's typical thing which is ready for dependency injection
because it has @injectable within the scope so that's cool.
We go ahead and create a simple method in here, which would help us in retrieving the data from the backend
server.
Let's create a method down here, that we can use to work the Hello World Service.
I call this execute hello world bean service.
Let's not really do anything.
It's just log execute hello world bean service.
Now what do you want to do?
We want to make use of this service in the welcome component.
So let's go with the welcome component.
And we would want to use the welcome the welcome data.
So we see it here how can we do that.
You need to use dependency injection.
Use your let's reformat this so that we can have multiple things clearly listed.
So I will say service... what you'd want to do, is use welcome data service. So let's go and import it in.
You see that there is a welcome data service which would be put it at the top.
service: WelcomeDataService that's cool!
What we want to do here, is we would want to call it i the getWelcomeMessage.
this.service.execute
HelloWorldBeanService
So is that what you would want to do.
remove this one because we don't really need it anymore.
That's what would happen, if it's going to this application.
Click... wait for it to relaunch... get.
So it's executing the Hello World Service.
It is not really written
The logic for it yet. What we do in the next step is focus on the logic for the higher level.
Let's see how to call the execute hello world bean service,  in the next step.
I'll see you in the next step.