Welcome back. In the previous steps, we connected todos page to the todo service from the back end.
We are now retrieving all the todos from the back-end.
So if you go with the back end, and make a change like this, so let's learn about Microservices 2.
Just to refresh the todos page again, you see oos home../. todoss.
You see the new data are getting reflected. In subsequent steps,
Let's focus on adding more features to our page.
Let's add delete update and add two new features.
Let's start with adding the delete feature in the next few steps. To be able to delete something you'd
want to have a servies exposed, what you are allowed to delete them. We have already decided that delete
/user/username/todos, and the ID of the two.
So let's just modify this a little. So let's make this something like this.
Where do we need to create this?
You need to create it in the todo resource.
So let's go back to the resource.. I'll paste this in. What we want to do, is we would want to create a
delete method. Before we create a delete method in the resource,
we need a delete method in the hardcoded service. So that we can collect and delete the todo
Let's quickly create a todo delete method... public...
Let's return the deleted todo back, so it would return the todo back. If we did not find that todo,
we'll return back.
So I'll say deleteById,  and pass the ID in, so long ID.
That's the id which we want to pass in, and we would want to delete the ID with this specific id.
So let's saty Todo todo = findByID(),  and I will create a method called find by id very soon and what we can do?
what we can do is todos.remove the to do which is fine
We don't really have the find by id method yet, and the other thing is todo.remove as the equals method.
We don't really have equal method defined on the todo
Let's go out and define, it so that you can do a right click generators... generate hash code in equals
and is just the id.
So I use just the ID to compare, if Id's are same, then todos are same.
You'd see that there are two methods to each injector: hash code and the equals. The importante logic
is in here.
So if IDS are same only then this would return true back. That's cool.
So we now have todo hardcoded service. doing a find by id,  and we are removing that todo.
But the find by ID is not yet defined, so can one create method find by ID ,and let's make it a public
method.
We'll get the todo by find by id, long id,  all looks good so let's go ahead and implement this method.
It should be simple iterations, right! so  for Todo todo :
Let's iterate through all the todos...and if todo.ID == ID.
Actually it should have todo..
Get ID().
== ID then.
return the todo back. If a matching todo is found, it would return todo back
Otherwise it would return NULL back.
And what does the delete Id do? it finds a todo by ID, and if todd == null
Let's return back right here.
And if we are able to successfully return the todo out, then we return todo back.
If you want to really be safe, then you can actually check the return value. if todo.remove() is successful,
then return true. Otherwise,
At the end you can say return null.
So what we're doing here is very simple checking.
At this point if we are able to find a todo at this point, we are checking if we are able to delete
the todo. remove returns true or false, based on whether it was successful at removing it.
If it was successfully removing, it then we are returning true back. Otherwise, we are returning null back.
Let's focus on the delete method.
In the to do resource
What should we be doing here?
We need to use the delete mappings, so @Delete mapping and let us use this .. user is present in here.
It was a name to user ID that looks good... and public.
Typically what should be the response to it, is that we should return from a delete method.
There are two options: either we can return success or we can return no content back.
So in this specific thing we choose the no content option response
Entity. Without any content response entity, unable to us to return a specific status back, or will we
return
The success status back? So we did not really need to use the response entity, because that's the default.
But now we want to return a specific status of the content back, and that's the reason why we are using
response entity, and the response entity of void,  and I'll say delete todo, and we would need to have two path variables
path variable string... the first one is username.
The second one is the ID..
It should be a long id,  and let's start the method down here.
There are a few compilation errors.
Let's work on it after we make the entire code visible.
Yep this is cool. control one... import delete mapping , control-1 or command-1 again, an import response entity
Cool the delete todo method.
It's not returning anything that's why
There's a compilation error. Let's call  todo service.delete by ID.. I'd delete ID...  ID method we have..
We are able to call it. let's assign the statement to a new local variable.
todo != null then it means it successfully deleted.
So i'll say return response entity.noContent().build()
We are returning a status of no content.
If you are able to successfully delete it. Otherwise it's returning response entity . not found status.
Actually we should return response.notfound() .
So what we are doing in here is we are invoking the todo service delete method.
If delete was successful, this would return a todo back.
And in other situation, we are retaining no content back. Either we are.
We are returning not fund status back.
One of the important parts of building RESTful services is deciding what status to use and
Response entity helps us to build specific requests with specific state assigned. And that's the reason
why we are making use of response entity in this specific request. In this step,
The resource method for delete. In the next step,
Let's try and this and see if we are successfully doing that.
I'll see you in the next step. Until then,
Bye Bye!