Welcome back. In the previous step, we created the delete method for the resource. In this step.
Let's try and execute it.
What we do is we use REST API client called restlet.
So if you search for restlet client, REST API testing,
You should find a good chrome plugin in of this kind.
Go ahead and install this.
I will install it.
Is that what you would see remove from Chrome.
But if you are not installed, then you would be able to see the Install button which you can use. So go
ahead and install it, and once you install it you'd see an icon like this.
If you don't see an icon like this, then you can click this and you should see an icon down here somewhere.
So it's this blue color icon which you've seen here.
And once you click this it would open up the restlet client it would....
The first page.
It's taking a while to load up the first page.
If this is not the first page you are seeing, then you would be able to do a skip.
You don't really need to create an ID to be using this.
So on the previous page, you'd be able to skip it and actually come into this specific thing.
What do you want to do, is we want to be able to execute a delete request, and the URL is localhost:8080 user
in28minutes/todos/
The id of the todo that you would want to delete.
So this is good, and now I create the send request and you see that I'm getting a 403.
When you look at the statuses,it is 403. forbidden. the  reason why this request failed is because
what the restlet client does is, it sent the origin as this specific.
URL. So since the origin is this.
And if you look at our specific configuration, we only allow requests from this specific origin.
So let's configure our origin.
And so the way we can do that is by saying origin, and we can specify the URl as 4200 and.
If you do send, you you'd see that the response is 204.  204 is no content and that's cool.
That means our request has executed successfully. Now if you go to the todos application, go to the
homepage and come back to the todo page.
You would see that our ID todo is deleted.
One of the important things that you need to remember, is each time this application is restarted. That
means every time you make a change in this application it restarted.
And every time it's restarted you'd see that the data would refresh. The data from the hardcoded so it
would be refreshed.
So each time what would happen is when I go to the home and todos, you would see the data completely
again. In this quick step, we focused on executing the delete request. In the next step, we enhance our
UI to be able to execute the delete request.
I'll see you in the next step. Until then, bye-bye!