Welcome back. In the previous step, we created the delete service.
We executed it.
And in this step, let's focus on the UI part on the front end. In fact, you would want to be able to call delete
from the UI.
How can we do that?
The first thing that you would need to do, is we need to enhance the To Do List component.
So let's go to the HTML, and what we want to do is we would want to do a header called actions.
So we would want to be able to invoke the delete.
So let's add our actions, and let's and DD... let's say over hear button and onclick of the button
add a method called delete
and let's say delete.
Let's see how this looks in the UI code.
This is how it looks.
And let's add a class=button, and btn and warning.
See how this looks.
This is how it looks.
We don't really need to say delete todo, because it's almost inherent that you are deleting todo. so
let's just have delete in here.
And now we need to define delete todo method.
Where do we need to do that, is todo component.
Let's go ahead and delete it. Define it in here, over here let's add delete todo method, and console.log
delete todo
Let's go to the console
And inspect... so that we can go to the console
Yeah this is good enough. When I do delete,
You can delete todo , and print it.
One of the important things that I would need to be able to identify, is which todo is being deleted.
The id of the todo being deleted that is very very important.
And the id of the deleted todo. All that I need to do is to say todo.id,  that because there's a variable called
todo which is already defined in here, and all that I need to do is say todo.
Id. Save this.
Now I can pass the ID in here. So I'll say id and delete todo.
And let's change it to ticks,  so that we can actually print a variable name. so delete todo
so we can print the value of the ID in here.
Save this and let's go to the last page, and see what would happen if you click delete. delete todo 1
delete delete todo 2,  delete todo 3.
That's cool.
So now we are able to execute... to execute the delete method on the right todo.
But this is just the UI part.
We would actually need to call this service.
So we need to enhance the todo.service, so that we can call todo service.
Right?
So let's create that method.
So delete todo the  method accepts two parameters.
I use that name comma the ID to be deleted.
So let's pass on those two parameters.
What we'll do, is do something similar to what we see for the Get method. So this.http.delete.
So that's the only difference. This is going to call the delete method.
And what is it that you want to call?
Let's use the same ticks, and the URL which you would want to call it.
Copy it from the restlet client, because that was a successful execution for us.
Let's take it from here.
So users.... instead of this,
It should be ${} username, and instead of todos/1,
We need to replace it with . add $.
This $ is very very important.
We make sure that you have a $ in both these places.
So this index is this, and you'd see that it's highlighted.
So if I'm making use of the variable in this string, then you'd see that it's highlighted.
Now let's go to that list component and enhance this.
So what we want to do in here, is we would want to say this. ... this.todo service. delete todo
And what are the parameters?
User name is the first one. Let's continue hard-coding to in28minutes, and what we want to do the ID is
the ID of the todo, we need todo.subscribe which would delete it.
Now what could we do when we delete the todo? If the successful response comes back?
What should we do?
Let's define this right now. So let's do a console.log of response so that we can see what is the
response.
And ideally it would show a message to the user, that delet todo has been successful.
What I'll do is create a simple message string, and here in the list-todos component the statement
below the header.
Just like in the login page. We did this already log in component.html. We have a warning in here.
So let's do something very similar in here.
So what we are doing is alert. We'll say alert some sort of warning when... and if condition would change
a little here.
What we are looking for the message... if the message exists, show the message at all here in the list-
todos component.
Let's go ahead and say console.log and this.message is equal to delete... you can also include
the ID in.
So I'd say tick,  so that you can actually say delete of todo... $  successful.
Let's see what would happen.
Let's go back to our UI now.
We have to delete.
let's clear out the console.
clear out the network, and and let's click delete.
You can see that it says delete of todo 1 successful.
That's cool.
One of the things you would see in here, is the fact that we are still seeing three todos.
We focus on it a little later, but for now let's look at the content.
It says delete todo 1  is sending a response of null,
that's OK.
And if I expand this further to see the network tab, you'd see that there is a response of todo for coming
in with just no content.
So localhost:8080 user in28minutes todos/1 DELETE
That's cool!
So this is all good.
And if you go and execute the todos link, you'll see that the ID 1 is deleted.
That's perfect.
So we are able to delete the todo. the one thing I didn't really like right now is the fact that we
are still seeing the complete list of todos.
Why is it so?
Because we have not really refreshed the todos list.
If you see that if actually click to do that again, or actually go to home and come back to todos
and do the refresh again, you would see that the todo is actually deleted.
So how do we get a refresh page once they are deleted?
What other ways would we do? Directly call this method again. So I can copy this code and call this again
inside the response. Once the response comes back.
I can do the refresh all the todos. But that would be too much, because we would be duplicating a lot
of code.
So what I do is I'll refactor this to an external method. So what I do is take this logic and actually
move it to a method. Instead of ngOnInit,
Let's create a method called refresh todos, and put the logic in there.
And what we do is on ngOnInit,  let's called refresh todos,
and we can do the same thing. When we actually
do this in. The other things you can actually do, is actually try and play with the todos, and delete the
specific ID from the ToDo List, which is present on the client side.
I would not recommend, because you would always want to reflect what data is on your server as much as
possible, unless you have a huge performance issue.
I think invoking the service again, and getting the data again is the better option.
Let's look at the thing again.
The todos are loaded.
You have todos. Click delete, the delete is successful.
Cool isn't it.
In the last few steps we focused on implementing the delete action, and we have update and the add new
todo actions remaining, in the next steps.
Let's create the update and the ad todo action.
I'll see you in the next step.
Until then, Bye!