Welcome back. In the previous step, we implemented the Delete todo. In this step and the subsequent steps
let's focus on update todos.
So we would want to add a feature to update a todo.
How do we do that?
Let's look at it in the next few steps.
Let's get started with updating the UI.
In this specific step. Let's go to the list-todos component.html,  and let's add a fresh button let's call
this delete.
And before they delete you would want to have an Update.
And here I'll copy this Delete. Exactly the same thing but instead of delete though, let's call it update
todo, and bnt- , instead of  warning, say  success.
And let's see how the screen looks.
Now you have an update button and the delete button.
It's up to you if you want to have the label.
Edit here.
A Bit later. But this looks relatively comfortable.
Let's get started with implementing the update.
Let's go to the list-todos component, and what we want to do is create something similar to this for
the update.
It should be.
update, and here.
console.log(), ticks, update.
id tick.
Typically what would happen when I click the update? We should go to the new screen. We'll implement that
very soon, after we check that our basic right.
You go to the console, and click update. and you can say update 1, update 2, update 3
What should I do on the update? Typically I should go to the next screen.
Right.
I should go to the screen, and I should be able to update the todo. What I need if I want to create a
new screen, what should I create?
Think about it.
You would need to create a new component.
Let's go out and do that and regenerate component.
And I call this todo, because it would be allowing us to edit or todo.
And later we'll also be using the same thing for creating a todo. So I'll call this component as just
todo. component todo. And you would see that there would be four files created, one file being modified
four files created: the CSS, HTML, and the code file .ts, and the app.module app
module, which is the root module, also contains the todocomponent so that basically the things which are
added in.
Now what we want to do, is we would want to route to the todo component when user clicks update. We would
want to send him to the component.
How do we do that?
First of all,  we need to define the route for the todos.
So how do we define a route for the todo component?
It's been a long time since we touched this module, because it's been a long time since we actually created
a component. Let's get down to here.
So I'll say path todos/:id . So which to do
So what I'm defining over here is todos/:ID, because I would want to have an ID which says
which todo is being edited, and the component is todo component I wanted to get that out. Got to
it because I dont want anybody to be able to get to this URL, without the route guard. Lets say this
now.
Let's go to the list-todos component.ts .  Over here, what we want to do, is we would want the route to that
specific screen.
How do we route that to screen?
We need to use the router. Long time since we played with the router. So private router:
Router. Let's import this in, So put a comma here so that it compiles, and if you go to the top router angular
/router. that's the import which we have done with  dependency injection successfully.
Now I can use the router in here.
So I need to, do what I need to do is,
this.router.navigate  We can pass an array, and the first thing which we have
in the arrsy is the name of the route to do. And to do this,  would want to actually pass in parameter.
So todo with a specific ID.
Lets see what would happen right there.
So I click on it and we are going to the todo.
/1.
Let's go to todos again and let's click update.
So it's going to todo/2.
If you click on it here, it goes to Todos/3. So routing is working.
However you would need to still implement the todo page. In the next step,
Let's focus on the todo page. Let's implement a form in here, and get a beautiful view. And I'll see you
in the next step.
Until then, bye bye!