Welcome back. In the step, let's define a simple view for the todo page.
Where do we go?
It's todo.component.html, and all here what do we need to do.
We would want to define our todo component. So I'll start with creating a div class = container
and over here, we would want to define two elements in the two page.
The first thing that we would want to see, is the description of the todo, and the other thing which
you would want to do, is the target date of the todo. We start with the description in a simple word.
I would have said input type = a text, name = a description.
And I would say this is required.
So this is basically all you need to do in a very simple world.
For the description field.
And similarly for the date field in particular, that name is going to target date, and target date.
Also is required to see the page. Right now if you have these two things coming up,
Don't really look very nice, right?
Let's add a h1 at the top too.
Let's start with making these a little bit better.
So I'd say class = form control.
This is one of the classes which is present in Bootstrap.
It looks a little better right now.
Let's create a fieldset to make sure that we have a label as well.
So we create a field to it, and we'll have a label for this.
So we'll have a label, and the label for this specific thing.
Let's have it as description
let's type in, and let's format the whole thing out, and let's have something similar for the type field.
So let's copy the field stuff out.
And this one, the label would be Target
Let's quickly look at how it looks.
Hopefully much better then earlier.
OK.
So we have a decent looking form.
Now I can select a date in here by clicking this.
If you're using a different browser, there might be a different way of selecting it.
But for now I can enter a description. I can enter a date that's decent enough.
Let's add another class which makes it even better.
class = form group
classes which we are all adding in are typical bootstrap classes, just to make you look a little better.
If I wait for the page to refresh.
This looks like a pretty decent form that we can work with.
Now let's add in a button at the top.
Actually not at the top, at the bottom, so that we can actually do the update.
I'll call this button Save, and let's add a class Button and Btn success because we are going to
save details.
That's fine.
And let's add in method call for this.
So on click of this button what do we do?
Let's invoke a method
Save todo.
Let's see how this looks like.
Now we have a pretty good looking page, where we can enter the description, I can edit todo.
But what we want to do, is we want to get the details of the existing todo, and throw them in here because
we are trying to update.
We are trying to update an existing todo, or we will want to get an update existing todo, and show it
in here.
In the next step.
let's focus on creating a service to retrieve the details of a specific target.
I'll see you in the next step. Until then, bye!