Welcome back. In the previous step, we wanted to get the details of a specific todo.
And we realized we don't really have a service to do that. So let's create a service quickly and let's
copy this.
So I would want to get the details of a specific todo. So and ID in and it's get mapping that's cool
get ofg all todos ...get todo and I would want the variable ID in.
So this is what we would want come up at the ID, and over here, what we want to do is todo service.
find ID, and get me the specific one with that specific ID.
And this would not return a list of todos, it would return a specific todo value back.  Done.
Easy, cool.
Now the server has picked up the change, and let us execute and see if we are able to execute the service. So
/todos/
1. cool! We were able very quickly implement the service to retrieve the details of a specific to do.
Now I would want to call this service, what should we do?
Let's go out to our todo service.
So todo data service. ts, is where we would need to go.
What we need to do, is we would want to do something very similar to delete. So actually copy this.
And this is actually a retrieve todo. What we would want to do is instead of delete, you want to do a get and
get the specific todo. well that looks good.
So we have retrieve todo method ready to do that.
So the service, we want to make use of it.
We want to make use of it in the todo component.
So when we are loading the todo,  we would want to get the details of todo. Let's igo down to todo component
todo . component . ts. What we want to do in here, we would want to use the service and get
the details.
Before that we would need to autowire it in. Use Dependency Injection, private todo service, and this would
be todo data service.
What do you want to do: this.todo service. retrieve todo we continue the tradition of
hard coding in28minutes and we will actually use the ID which comes from the service.
So the id actually coming in as part of the path variable,  of our application.
But we have not really saved it in, so we'll do that.
So lets have a ID number in here.
We need to get that Id very soon.
So for now lets put one in here so that we do.
And I actually would want to put the ID in here.
Its getting me a compilation error, because I need to say this.id
Now what do you want to do once I have the data and I get the data in? what I want to do?
You have to do thing in here, so as the todo todo import the  todo in.
And I would say this.todo = ... first I need to have the data on it, so say data. once I have the
data structure, data =  you can see that it's complaining.
The object is not a todo type. todo what I do is I'll go to the retrieve todo and well here in the get
I would need to declare the fact that the data structure to which it can map it to, Now you would
see that this would compile fine.
So what we're doing is quickly creating the steps needed to be able to initialize the todo, and other
things.
One of the reasons we are missing right now, is we have not really got the id yet. where we want
to get the id from? We would want to get it from the route parameters.
If we look at the welcome component, we did this already earlier.
How do we get it from our component? So you can see that we have added activate route as a parameter and
got the value in this way.
So let's look at doing something very similar right now.
So private route : ActivatedRoute,  insert a comma here.. to make sure that compiler is happy and now, You
have actual router imported from angular/route.
That's good.
And now I can use that router
So the parameter name in here is  id. params is nothing but a map, and from the map I'm picking up something
with the key as I.D. and that's what becomes this.id
So we are setting the this.id in here, that we are calling directly to do so.
And as soon as that is available, we are setting it to local todo.
Is that too efficient?
No we would need to map our view to this.
How do we do that?
So we have the description field, how do we map it to the view?
Think about it> banana in a box. We used that in the login page.
So I'll say todo.description
ngModel. And this one would be something similar.
Todo.
target
Isn't this cool?
All the concepts that we have learned over the period of the last few hours, we are combining all of
them., and using them to create this todo for them.
Now let's see if everything is coming up fine.
Now you can see that. Let's run this. is good.
Now this is working fine.
Learn to dance todo.  it working fine, but I'm not able to show the target date.
And when I look at the log it says 2000 1 8 0 9, it does not conform to the required format.
Y y y y m m d d .
What do you think? is the format of the day is not really good? what does it do?
The reason is because the service is returning the date in this specific format.
In the next step,
Let's look at how to fix this.
But for now what we have in here is a pretty decent set of data.
I can click update in here.
Look at that specific update details there.
So now I can go back to the todos page, click Update Learn about microservices,  and click Update again and learn
about angular.
That's pretty cool.
One of the things which we have been doing over the last few steps, is kind of hard coding in28minutes
when we get to the authentication section,
We'll try and remove all the hard coding, and really make our application compatible with multiple users.
For now stick with us, and I'll see you in the next step.
Until then, bye bye!