Welcome back. In the previous step, we started creating our retrieve todo service.
And we were able to see the todo description. But however, we were getting a couple of errors in the console.
If you look at the console, it said this target date value did not match.
And also if you look a little up, then you would see that it's saying cannot read properly the description
of undefined. When i click this todo competen.html, it was mapping it to the that description.
So you can see that the todo's description is maped to an error.
Why is this happening, and what are the fixes for these?
Let's look at them in this specific step.
Let's look at the second problem. For a todo or description is giving an error.
Why would it give me an error? When I actually end up seeing the data in there?
The thing is we need to look at how we are loading the data for this todo component. this is the way
are loading it is by using a subscribe().
So we are asynchronously calling this.
So this update method say it's OK when the data is available do this.
But our ngOninit() method is completed execution.
It would directly start loading up the todo component.html
So at that point the object might be null, and that's the reason why to do that description is giving
an error.
What we do, is create initial todo object. So what we will say this.todo = new Todo
take Dummy ID,  and let's have dummy description, and let's say done is false and let's pass new date as
the default.
Now if I look at the screen right now, when it refreshes on the console, you'll see that there is just
one error present.
The reason is because even though we don't really see these details, that this todo we'll never be able
to see.
So if you actually go to todos and click on it, you'd see that actually empty, where you are NOT be
able to see.
So your user will not be able to see it, unless you are so very very slow.
So if user is very very slow, then probably then you would be able to see the specific details.
But having this default would ensure that the user would be shown something very quickly.
So the user experience will be much better.
Let's get to the second problem.
The target did this specific thing.
What we have the problem, is this is not having the right format. how can we get it to have the right
format?
We talked about pipes earlier, so I can go to the html, and can I say it's my pipe.
Not the description field.
Actually the target date  field,  can I sat targetDate | date?
Will this work?
Oops!
It doesn't even compile, because ngModel needs to be mapped to a basic model element. One of the things
is this ngModel is actually a combination of two things.
What we do now is we'll split this into those two parts to you. And the first one is the proper binding
and ngModel =  todo.targetDate. Second one is the event binding.
Whenever this specific model changes, set the todo.target date to the changed value, $event.
So when we talk about ngModel anywhere, it's actually two things.
The first one is property binding, ngModel is equal to this.
The second one is the event binding. Whenever you change the target date value.
Then set the target date to whatever values returned by the event, and refresh the page.
I hope to see the error get gone..
So I think the date should be in this specific format.
YYYY
MM DD. So we would want to convert the value of this into that specific format, so we use a pipe. And what
is in this specific date format?
And it just use a colon within single quote, put YYYY
So what we're doing is converting target date into that format, so that that format can be shown as
a date.
Cool.
Now if we are able to see the description, we are now able to see the target date and our console does
not really have any error.
Let's look at a few other todos, to make sure that everything is working fine.
Home/todo is update.
Cool.
I'm able to see the details of this update.
I'm able to see the detail of this, to show you we can see that there are no errors in the console, so that's
cool.
So everybody's happy and I'll see you in the next step.
Maybe you should focus on saving this data back.
I'll see you in the next step.
Until then, bye!