Welcome back. In step, let's get started with creating the update service, so that when we click Save, we
can call the update service.
Let's go to eclipse.
We need to start with the todo.service, to create the update.
So what we'll do, is let's create a method down here.
It is public todo.
And I'll call this save todo,  And tdo. In JPA, same method is used to do the update and the inserts
as well.
So at a later point, we'll check the id of the todo. the id of the todo is -1.
The idea of the todo is -1.
Then it means we will want to insert it in.
Let's not worry about it right now.
What we want to do, is when we really have a todo with a different id, what we need to do? We
would want to update it.
This is just a static list.
So to make it easy for us, if we would do the update is by calling delete ID, and passing the todo.
getID(). So I'll delete the todo with that specific ID, and I will add the new todo in, and say todo.
add().
So what would happen?
The old todo was deleted, and the new todo is added.
So I'm kind of taking a shortcut in here, otherwise you would want to add the todo.
So if it's a new todo with an ID -1, that means I would want todo add.
But before that I would also set the id.
So I set the ID. So what should be the ID? ++Id go to the ID and put it in.
And in all the cases, what we'll do is we'll return the updated todo.
So what we are doing here is creating a simple Save method.
This helps us to
add a new todo. When I'm adding a new todo,
I'm just incrementing the counter and adding it in. When I have to update it.
Then what I'm doing is first delete and then adding it.
There's kind of a shortcut way, instead of taking each attribute and adding value.
I'm just adding deleting it and updating it in.
Now let's go to the resource and create both the methods. We'll create one method to do the add and one method
to do the update.
We already have the details for it through source.
We decided this a little earlier.
So let's go out and paste this in.
So to add it we want to use a put, and to create a new rule we want to use a post, and that's the standard
which is used when it comes to RESTful services.
Let's start with the update method.
So let's say @UpdateMapping, and what's the URL? is it todos update mapping.
So I use this syntax as it is.
So I'll just copy this stuff from here to here.
Now I have the update mapping being present in here.
They should be update todo. Instead of the  update mapping, actually I should have used put mapping.
I'll update this mapping, control-1,  @PutMapping, we have the update todo body ready. We're
not really doing anything yet, so really get a user name, id,  and variable username, ID that's cool.
And along with the update to do we'll get a request body. In the request body,
So we would have the updated content that is sent as part of the request body, and of the type todo.
So let's add these in as well, in the body for the update request.
We will typically send an OK status, with the content of the updated todo.
So what I'll do, is I'll do a response entity of todo, it's not a  void.
It's Todo.
And now let's call the todo service.save(), and passing all the values off to that.
And this would return the updated todos.
Let's take the updated value of the todos,  to update it and let's return a new Response entity containing
a todo. We populated the todo.
And say Http Status.OK. Actually the same thing can be done by just saying return todo,
and changing the return type to todo as well.
But this was good.
This gives us more options. In future if you want to extend this and be able to return other status back
then using the response entity gives us more options.
Now that we have created the mapping for this ,let's look at how to create the POST mapping in the next
step. Until then,
Bye Bye.