Welcome back. In the previous step, we created the mapping request.
Let's test it first, before we would go ahead and create the POST mapping. Before we do anything let's do
a get, and get the details of specific ideas so let's say todos/1.
Make sure that you have the origin 4200 in here.
You'd see that the response is 200, and I'm seeing the response back in it.
So I copied the body from here, so that we can use it in our request.
So I'm changing it to put, and inside the body I'm copying it whatever I've copied from here.
What i'll do, is the id 1, I would want to change it and let's say it's learning to dance.
Done. And let's try and update it. Let's call send now.
You would see I'm getting a 500.
It says Type definition error,  simple type.
Todo has no creators
That's what it says.
The reason why you are getting the error, is because todo does not have a default constructor. One
of the things is if it wanted to have something as a request body, then you'd need to actually have a
default constructor with no arguments, present that would enable creation of this object.
And then what are the values in the request application does that does it for them?
You could just have some constructor like this.
You have to create a default constructor.
Now let's go ahead and let's do that request again.
Send nothing.
You'll see that the execution of the request is successful : it says 200 and we are able to get the content
of the request back.
And if I go and refresh the in28minutes todos URL,  what we see? learn to dance  , 15.
That's cool.
So our update request logic is working.
Now let's focus on POST request which is used to create a new todo. Copy Put mapping whole thing again.
This one we would want to use the POST mapping post mapping.
And what I would need to do is the POST mapping? you send the POST. What you would send a todo, you
will get an error, because you will not have ID.
We need to assign the ID inside the application for it.
So let's remove that out, and over here, what we want to do is the save meothod.
Let's call Save method, let's call it.
However what we want to do for a created resource is the location of the created resource.
So what we would typically return for a created post request, is what do you want all of the created
resource.
So what we can do is we can actually get rid of the current resource.
So what we can do is get current resource?
So if the URL resource for this one is localhost:8080, it was  in28minutes/ytodos
Now to this I can up the ID, and that would give me the URL of the new resource, which is great.
So to this if I can actually append in the ID, then this would give me the complete URL.
So lets see how to do that.
There is a helper component called ServletsUri
Actually it's the ServletUri. Just type in ServletUri, a  component builder that's the component.
And inside there are static methods, and you can say.
So you have a component builder, and you can say from the current request. but from current request you
can request and append this particular thing up... and Id: what I would want to append is the ID of the
created resource very quickly.
So this is created. The  resource I created to post the created resource to this.
The way you can do that is by saying . build and expand and build and expand,  because passing the variable
value.
So I'll just press enter, so that we can go on to the next line.
So what I'll do is I'll pass in the created todo.getId().
So the id of the created todo will be replaced.
This will be replaced with the id of the created todo.
And let's get the URI. Let's get the URI, and I can do one and send it to a local variable so I can
this URI, and over here, what we'll do is let's do the static method.
I'd want to do  response entity.create() what is created?
URI location is created, and . build().
Let's quickly review what we have done until now.
So we called the Save method, and we got the details of the created todo. The same method if we look
at it.
What does it do?
It checks if it's -1.
And if it's -1,  then it's new todo. Actually by default the value of the ID would be equal to
zero or -1. I would consider it as if the request is to create a new todo.
And what we are doing is zero or -1.
We are actually setting the id of what the new todo, So i'm incrementing the counter.
And we are adding it to the list of todo's, and what we and at the end we also return that back.
So what we do in here, we get the created todo, and what we are doing in here is taking the current request
back and appending /id.
So we want to add the ID in, and we are creating the resource.
So we return a status called created Response Entity, create it,  and passing in the new todo.
The URI which is created,  .build()
Now if you save this and let's go to the editor and go to the restlet client, we sent a put request with
this content.
What we do now,  is I would want to create a post, but in the post you should not send the ID in.
So in the post we would want to create a new resource. So we don't really know the id of the resource.
So I want to create a post request, and I would say learn to ride a bicycle,  Make sure that you have the
right origin and the content type set.  Application json,  and location localhost:4200.
Now the URL of the post on the other hand is just todos.
So user in28minutes.  So check everything here, so POST mapping user in28 minutes todos, and that
would be mapped to the user name and the request.
Thats cool.
Now click send.
And let's see what happened.
You're getting a request.
You are getting a response of.
201, and you're getting.
URL back as well.
The great thing about returning the location URL, is that I can open up a new tab.
Yupe in the URL, and I can see the details of the new todo.
You can see that it has an ID 4,  and all that stuff as well.
Now if you want to create another todo, I can say learn to write learn to drive cars.
And let's say send. You can see that it's doing one and not the id that it is five.
So if you take this and if you actually put it in here, you would see that it's learned to drive a car
and if I the user in28minutes todo,  request.
You would see that it's returning five todos back.
So what we have done in the last few steps, is implemented the services that you would need for doing
the delete.
We did the delete, the put and the Post, what we're trying to do in here is we are trying to follow
the HTTP standards. The delete method typically returns no content when it's successful.
And if it's failing, then it would return not found. The PUT request would return a status of OK with
the content of the updated resource and the created resource.
When you tried to a POST, what it does is it returns the status as created, and returns the URL
of the created resource.
These are basically the standards which I used when we create resources.
What we have done over the last couple of steps, is to create the resource and update the resource.
we want to update the todo, and create todo, so we quickly created these services so that we can focus
on the front end in the next few steps.
I'll see you in the next step. Until then, bye-bye!