This video,
Let's quickly evaluate a few best practices in RESTful services.
The first and the last best practice is consumer first.
Always think about the user.  Can you have a clear idea about who you are consumers are?
Is it a web application?
Do you expect a mobile application coming in in the future? And have a clear idea of what they want before
you name your resources.
Think from the perspective of your customers. What do they think about those resources?
Will they be able to understand the naming of your resources?
The simpler it is for your consumer to understand your services, the better it is for you.
Last but not least have great documentation for your apps.
Swagger is one of the most popular documentation standard for RESTful APIs. But whatever standard you are
using,
Make sure that your consumers understand the documentation that you produce.
The next important best practice is make the best use of whatever HTTP provides.
The RESTful services based on HTTP make the best use of the request.
Use the right request method appropriate for your specific action.
Get post put and delete and ensure that you are sending a proper response status back when a resource
is not found.
Do not send a server error
When there is a bad request, when there is a validation error not in the server, send a bad request 400.
When you create a resource do not send just success,  send created back.
Think about what is the appropriate response status for your situation.
Ensure that there is no secure info that is retained in your case.
Things like SSL,  just don't go by the standard definition.
Think about what you're putting in the URL,  and make sure that there is nothing secure that going in
your case.
Always use plurals.
For example in the course, we always used /users.
It is that we created was /users/1.
Not /user/1
I really prefer using the plurals, because it's more readable than using the singular when you think resources.
Think nouns, it's user, it's account.
It's not delete user, it's not delete account.
Think about nouns and when you talk about resources.
Think about noun's. How you are thinking about nouns? it's all not always possible right.
There are always exceptions in.
For example if there's a search link on the web page, how do you do that for all these exception scenarios?
have a consistent approach.
If you are searching through something, then if you are searching for users, then say /users/
search.
So on the resource, have the actions defined.
For example this is how github does a star on the gists.
So if I put a star on the gist,  the way it sends the request is to the resource to just send the request
with star in the URL,  and the same thing in the delete.
If I understand something, this is the request goes out to define a consistent approach of how you would
want to handle the exception scenarios.
Things that don't fit into the nouns. What we looked at in this step are some of the best practices.
in RESTful design.
Most important thing: consumer first!