Welcome back. The last step, we created the basic framework. In this step, let's focus on really working the
Hello World Service.
Now how do we work this out? Angular provides a module called HTTPClientModule
And as part of it we have something called HTTPClient
We can use the client to get, post, delete, put: all kinds of HTTPP requests. All that we need to say is
OK this is the URL, and this is the data.
Let's use that in this,
And the subsequent steps.
Let's get the HTTPClient in here.
So how do they inject it in? add it to the constructor.
Right I'll say private http: HTTPClient.  so you can see that HttpClient is coming
in here. Make sure that it's coming in from an @angular/common/http
There is another HttpClient which is present in here. If you go a little down it's coming from selenium.
web-driver/http. So make sure that you're using the one from the angular/common/http.
If this client is not really listed.
All that you need to do is just put @ in here and make sure that you are putting this important
to import HTTPClient
This is part of a module angular/common/HTTP.
So the client does not automatically appear.
Make sure that you do this, it would be cool.
Now we have the http client imported in, and now let's go to work. this.http.get()...
one which you would want to do that. We would want in a GET request to what URL? to Hello World.
Isn't it easy?
Doesn't this look very easy? or it will return this back.
let's remove
this log, we'll not need it anymore.
So let's return this thing back. And what we'll do is, in the welcome component let's do a log of this.
So what we did is welcome back from the service.
We are trying to log.
Is that what we're doing
Let's see what would happen.
OK.
When I when I go to the page and refresh it
I see error.
It says No provider for HttpClient
So what it's saying is the client is not really available.
Why is it not available?
Think about it... think about the concept of an alert for an angler application. To make use of a component
or a utility from a module,
What do we need to do?
We need to import that module in.
The thing is we have not really imported the module in the way... we need to put it in in app.module
.ts
And the module that you need to import in, is HttpModule. It's HttpClientModule
So you can see that it's from angular/common.http.
So let's do that. imporitng this module into our app module
Make sure that you have this import. So the import client module... http client module from angular/common
/HTTP.
Now save this and go ahead.
And again when you log in and click to get the message, you would see that there is an observable which
is printed out to the console.  so interesting!
Right!
What is happening is, an observable is printed to the console.
And when I go to the network, clear it by using the clear and again to get a message, you're seeign that no activity
is taking place in the network. You can see what other requests which are sent from the client
application.
So for applications from the front end application, to the back and application.
And as of now, you can see that there is no request going out.
However when I go to the console whenever I press get welcome message, you see that there is an observable
which is getting logged.
This call is not going over the network.
What is happening in here? Lets look at that in the next step.
Until then, bye!