Welcome back. In the todo page, we have the feature to update it, but the save feature we have not really
implemented it, and are able to say what you need to call the request.
And in the previous step we implemented the post mapping.
Let's look at how to call the put method to update the details of the todo. Let's go to visual studio code.
And what we want to do is focus on the save.
So we want to create this save todo method.
Let's go to the todo.component.ts component.ts is what we are looking for, and over
here we want to do, is we will want to save the todo, and to be able to save that todo, what we want to
do is we would want to call the data service to do that.
So we should expose put method.
Let's see if it's there right now.
It's not really there.
So let's go out and create it.
I'll take the retrieve  todo, and use it to create the PUT TODO lstuff. so put todo.
Or if you will want to say update todo,  fine! update the new username, ID and I would want the details
of that todo to be updated. that very important like whatever details of the todo.
Needs to be saved to the database, I need to say that too.
So I need to do it all here.
We don't really get. What we would do is put. If you look at it, it's saying this compilation error, because it's
saying expect a todo three arguments.
Let's start putting the second argument which is the body.
So you can see that it's the body and the body we want to pass it to itself.
So we want to pass todo as part of the body of the request.
This is similar to how we did it in the restlet client, right ?when we need a post we put it in here
containing the body of the todo to be updated, so that later,  that the body needs to be put inside the
request when we make the request.
So I'll just put in there, so that it's very clear that we are putting these parameters in.
I want to make use of this update todo method.
Where do I want to make use of it?
Inside the todo component.
So let's get started reading that this update todo.
OOPS! Not do really have to do this but todo so is not true.
And what we need to do is we need to call the update todo with a username,  ID And so this username
ID comma,  todo or actually this.todo, and what we need to do once we call it? we need to subscribe
to it right?
To subscribe to it to make the call.
And what does the update todo return back? update todo return back, what does it return back?  it returns
back the updated todo.
So once you get the data back,
all that I need to do is do a console.log data now.
In addition to this, if I want to do more in the subscribe, what I can do, is I can actually put a brace and closing
this to write more statements.
For now let's just log. It really do a lot more than that. Let's see what happens.
Let's go to the todo page,  and say save.
Let's change it to 25.
And to refresh.
You can see that learned todo, and 25.
So the todo with ID 1 is updated.
That's what you see in there.
Let's see if the target date or date is working 2000.
Let's say I would want to pick the date, and let's say I would want to pick November 30th 2018, and save
it.
Let's call this to check if... Cool! November 30.
2018.
So this is working fine.
Now if I do right click inspect, and see the log, you would see that an object is being printed with all
the detail that we would expect. So description, done, the target date and that's cool.
And if we had network enabled and we did save
you would see that we as an input request for this.
And you can see that request payload also in here. When you go down and you'd see that the response status
code is 200.
And the response contains these details.
Awesome so we are able to make their respective changes that are needed to update the todo. Wo when
you click save.
The details are being updated.
But what I would also want to be able to do, is when I click save, I would want to be able to go back
to the todos page.
How can I do that? I can do that is by using the router.
So private router.
Let's take the router in.  You know where the router is coming from it's from angular/ router.
And now in addition to this, what we want to do is this is .navigate().
Where do you want to go? todo.
Let's see what would happen? refresh the page
and say... oops! Up there is a small syntax error... in what I have done.
Actually it should have been a method call,  I forgot to put parentheses around it, and that caused
the problem.
So is is out router.navigate. And pass in an array.
So let's see what would happen.
Let's wait for the whole thing to refresh.
Ok cool.
Click Save
OK.
I'm going back to the screen, so let's update learn about angular,  23.
Save it.
Cool!You see learn about angler , 23 at the bottom now.
Now let's change the date.
Click here.
And you'd be able to select the specific date
So 15,  and so on and so forth.
So we are now able to update and delete the todo.
And in the next step, let's focus on adding new todo to  that as well.
We are making a lot of progress and I'll see you in the next step.
Bye-bye!