Welcome back.
There is just one feature which is left in this specific app to really make it a complete app.
That's basically the ad, too.
I mean, there are a lot of stuff out on security that we'll discuss a little later.
And also, we did not really talk about database until now.
So we need to add and stuff a little later.
But from the features perspective on the actual functionality perspective, let's look at adding up
to do right enough.
So let's add a button here for adding a two and let's call the post method to create a new two.
And let's get that going.
Let's go to Jill's record and let's start with creating a new button.
Let's take the button that we already created.
And what I'll do is, oh, here at the bottom of this specific table, I create another div and take
glass is equal to raw.
And have my button down there.
And this would actually add to add to.
And and I would want it to be success, right?
Why do we really want it to be warning?
Cool.
Let's see the page.
Pretty decent.
Now let's create the add to the method, where do we implemented to lose Dort component?
This is where it would go.
What we would want to do is add two and two to add it to do, we don't really need to have anything
right now.
So what we'll do is we'll just take the user to the to do speech.
However, for the ad to do what I'll do is I'll pass the ideas minus one.
So in that application, let's how all the ideas to be positive.
And when the ideas minus one.
Let's assume that the user is trying to do.
And to do this, would it help us to use the component that we have already created.
So enough when I click add to the what happens.
Books.
Apps that make inspect error.
What error is it.
Compulsion.
Error.
Let's see what it is all about.
Cannot read property ideas of undefined.
What is happening.
When I click add to do to do that.
Idee.
Huh?
That's the problem.
What we did was when we copy pasted it, we forgot to actually remove what to do today.
But we don't really need to do Heidi.
Right.
So let's fix that and let's get back to where we were.
Let's add.
OK, good enough.
I'm able to go to the next screen.
The thing is, if you look at the console, you'll see that there is an error.
It says cannot read description often.
And if you go to the network, go back and add.
Let's clearly cancel right enough.
Let's try and add it to do you see that there is a request going into minus one?
So this is not really good because he's actually fighting a request.
Why is it fighting a request?
Because that's what we told it to do in two court component.
Dotty's drank a lot to do that component, Dr. Pierce.
And what does it to do that competent teachers do?
When you pass in an I.D., it actually tries to quality it.
It seems to what I do is, oh, here we said this third I.D. is equal to we got the idea from the parameters
and oh, here we created it with the hardcoded one.
Instead of that.
I think it's a better thing to do desert I.D. in here so that we use the I.D., which is coming in to
create the to do the other thing which we want to do is we would only want to call this if to do is
if the to do I.D. not dispense equally.
So if this dot I.D. not equal to minus one only then, then you'd want to call this specific thing.
So I'll put this in if.
So that when it's a neutral, you don't really need to call the retreat to do so, used to get the details
of it.
And the other thing is when we do a save.
We need to exactly do similar condition to if if this third I.D. is equal is equal to minus one.
Then what do we need to do?
We not need to actually call update.
We need to color create or else we need to call update.
So let's format this and get this right here.
We need to call create to see if to do that.
Idee is a political two minus one.
Then create otherwise update and same thing down here as well.
So here we are saying these are ideas equal to we are getting it from the usual parameters, sorted
out parameters and we are creating a default to do to represent it while we are getting it from the
service.
And if the idea is not minus one, then you need to get it.
Otherwise, we agree on you to do so.
We don't really need to get the values from the database.
Let's see if this is all working out fine.
Now to do minus one.
Okay.
I don't see any arrows down here.
That's cool.
This is the default that I wouldn't want to see.
Two to one.
Cool.
I'm seeing the details of one.
So both of them are working finally.
Go back to two minus one, because that's what we would want to focus on the new to do.
Now, if I click save, we don't really have anything implemented yet, because if you do that, if
this variety is visible to minus one need created to do.
But they're not done it yet.
Creating the create is very similar to the update to do.
Right.
So create two.
And you don't need to pass an I.D. and the UI role would not have the idea as well.
And instead they put it up post.
That's cool.
Now, let's go back to true component and make a call.
So how do we make a call?
This is.
Create to do.
I don't need to pass in the I.D..
And there is data coming back.
I would just need to log it and I would need to rout it back to the truth.
That's good.
So we don't really need to do anything else.
Let's look at it right now.
Let's wait for the whole thing to refresh.
I guess it has already refreshed and lets in to learn Microsoft uses a gain and save.
Cool.
Let's see if I have learned Microsoft.
Is this again down here.
Cool.
I see.
Learn Microsoft is is again down here.
That's awesome.
Right now.
She does this.
Let's try and update this so you can see that it was a sign that idea or for.
Let's update it lent again.
Forward save.
Cool.
You can try and test it a little more.
And now we have most of the features that we would want.
We have the update feature, the lead feature, and we can add a new to do as well.
Congratulate yourself and I'll see you in the next step.