Welcome back. In the previous steps, we added all the features that are typically necessary at a high
level, for managing your todos.
We are now able to update, delete and add todos as well.
But one of the things you would have observed already, is when I press enter in here...  in the description
field and I press enter.
Typically I would expect the form to be submitted.
The other thing you would notice is, when you click Save button I'm able to enter empty todo and save
todo it.
And even when I'm updating it I'll be able to save it without description.
And actually you'd be able to see it even with add todo.
So if I say save now, you have to do that.
Doesn't have a description and a target date, and that's not really a good situation to be in.
Right?
Let's improve the form to have important functionality.
One is when you press enter, you want to be able to submit the form. Two, when you have press save.
You would want to validate, we would have basic validation.
And we would want to make sure that they are validated before we are able to see the todo out.
Let's get started now.
The first thing we focus on is when I press enter, I would want this form to be submitted.
The interesting thing is now we don't really have a form in our page at all! Let's open up todo and we
see that there is not really a form that's pleasant in here.
So this is when you are using, and you know you don't really need a form, because you are not really submitting
anything our Todos.
But when you want to utilize the form features, like when I pressed enter inside any of the fields,  I would
want to submit the form typically like this,  In those kind of situations we would need a form. Let's add a
form in quickly.
So from and /form that basically the syntax, and I'll put all the important things in the form and
let's select all the code within the form, and type it in.
And I would want this one to be a submit type=submit.
And when you have a submit button inside the form, what we will do is we'll not really need to handle
the button click event.
What we do is we just make it on the form, so form we will add a submit event will say onSubmit
is equal to the same thing that we were doing earlier. So instead of click what we are moving it to is
onSubmit(). So what we're saying is when this form is submitted on  the submit event.
So make sure that you get the syntax right. So form and you submit is in save todo.
We removed that from here, and we added a type-submit so that the submit button gets called
by the form.
Now let's save this, relaunch  the application and press enter.
You'd see that as soon as I press enter, the form gets submitted and let's do submit and save.
And now you would see that both the save button, and as well as enters, work
So now we are able to submit the form just by pressing enter.
That's good.
Now that one problem solved. We have one more problem remaining.
That's basically the validation. We would want to make sure that only when this form is valid, we would
want to have this form to be submitted.
How can I do that?
Now I want to check that this form is valid in Angular?
There are some things called template variables.
You would need a template variable on this form to identify this form and check logic around it.
And the template variable I would create is  #todoform =  and this is "ngForm". So
what you are saying is have this entire form,  in this template.
This variable is kind of a reference to this entire form.
Now what I want to do, is I want  saveTodo only if this form is not invalid.
So let's quickly write this code.
I'll explain this in a little while.
What we are doing is we are creating a reference variable.
So this is a template variable, but you can use this within this template anywhere.
And what we are using it here is to check if it's invalid.  When you have a form.
It provides a lot of features on it.
One of the features is to check if it's invalid. Todoform.invalid ... if from has any invalid
data, then todoForm.invalid would be true
What I'm saying is, submit it only if not of invalid.
So the form is valid then go ahead and do the save todo. The other thing is we already added a few validations
in we said required.
So we said this date is required.
It's just that these were not executed
earlier.
So you would see that even the description field said it's required.
So let's now check the form and see what would happen.
Let's save this.
And now let's open up the update and press enter.
Now you would see that when we press enter, the form doesn't get submitted.  The form gets submitted only when
I enter something in,  let's save.
Nope.
When I say target date and select the date, only when I select the date I'll be able to save that. Now,
Isn't that awesome!
The awesome thing is all these features are built in into Angular.
So we're just moving out the click event, and making it ngSubmit on the form, and making the button
this type submit.
We were able to get a lot of functionality, and actually support a few other validations as well.
For example I can say minlength = 5.
I'm saying for the description field, the minimum length is 5.
So now, the minimum length of the description field is 5.
So if you enter less than four characters, then the form will not be submitted.
In this step, we look at the basic features around validating the forms.
There are a number of other awesome features which will be looking at in the next step. Until then, Bye Bye!