Welcome back. In the previous step, we looked at some of the basic validation features. In this step,
Let's look at a little bit of more about validation.
Now one more thing which we can improve on, is if I press enter here, or if I press the save, if I'm not
showing any validation message to the user and that's not really good right?
So let's start with actually having an indication of invalid fields.
And slowly we would add the validation messages. Also what I i'll do is open up this is this file todo component
.ts
And what I would want to do is say .ng-invlaid.
This is a class which is automatically added by Angular, on invalid fields.
And what I would want to do on invalid fields, I would want to add border on the left hand side of the
field... and the border let's make it 5px,  solid and let's give it a color # let's just say it's
red.
Save it and now refresh the page.
It's just not yet refreshed
It's refreshing now. Page is refreshed, and now you'd see that there is a red border on everything
which is invalid.
The description is empty, so it's invalid.
There is no red border on the target date.
But we have a form and the form is invalid, and because of it there is a red line for the entire form.
So everything which is invalid is getting visible.
And now if I just type in learn, you will see that the red bar disappears because this field is no longer
invalid.
And if this field is no longer invalid, then the entire form is also no longer invalid.
Isn't it cool? Just by adding a little bit of code,   we are able to do a lot of stuff.
Now the interesting thing is I don't really like the fact that when minimal length is 5,.
So when I am with the fifth character, this field becomes invalid so the form becomes invalid.
And I don't really need to show the whole thing in here. And CSS supports that, you just need to say
I'm not doing this on the form element.
So on the from element, do not apply this class. Cool!
Now only the invalid elements have there.
So if I go here and press delete on that, then and you would see that the target date field is also in
getting highlighting that specific thing
This is very cool right!
So a clear indication to the user as to which fields are invalid.
The other thing you can do is actually add validation messages on top of the form.
What I do is I'll say div class=alert. alert warning.
And if *ngIf=form todoForm.invalid, then I would say enter a valid user.
Let's see what would happen now if the form has invalid values, and you're trying to add valid values
in here right? Now let's say if I type in lear.
Are we having an length of five?
So as soon as I enter n, that you would see that that message disappeared.
The other thing you can do is actually, like now what happens is to refresh the entire page.
I'm trying to create a new todo.  By default,
It shows up in values. What I can do is I can tell when you show that when a field is edited. So don't
initially show it. but only show it when a field is edited. So todo form that will be there when at least
one value on the form is being changed.
So now you would see that by default it's not shown.
I entered learn.
So it is a valid value so it disappears. let's say learn about angular, and save it. Now,
When you do that then I come over here, and let's start removing the things that it doesn't really matter.
But when I change the value, it says enter valid values, and the invalid values are highlighted
by red color.
Now there are a few other things you can do.
You can actually add template variable on each of these elements as well. So I can say this element has
a template where it will show on the target date I can say #target date
= ngModel. Then what we are saying is we are creating a reference to this.
And what we can do now is I can use this reference in the validation as well. So I can say if todoForm
dot
And now I can take target date.invalid .  target date is invalid I can say enter a valid target date
and I can do something similar on the description as well as I can that description.invalid and
there at least 5 characters in this.
So all these are possible.
One of the things is for description, we did not really add template reference, so I would need to say #
description = ngModel.  Let's press ENTER or here so that we can see the entire field.
OK.
So this is the description of that specific thing,  for you.
What we have in here now is a detailed validation.
You would have a lot of messages displayed when something is invalid.
So you would see that when I do this, you can see the invalid values, that at least five characters in
description. If I actually go here and delete them, you would see all these values.
What we're showing in here is what are the wider range of possibilities that are possible with angular
when you design you a form, you might not need this kind of explicit... so many validation. So you can decide
how you would want to show the validation messages.
The idea is just to show what are different possibilities. In this specific step,
what we learned is how to validate the forms, and how we can make sure that when somebody tries to submit
when somebody presses Enter, we try and submit the form so that when I enter a valid value and press
enter the form gets submitted.
The we don't really have a target date, so let's put a target date and present enter.
Now I press and the form gets submitted and the change is good to see.
The other thing which we have added is validation on all these fields inside the form.
I'm sure this would have been an interesting exercise for you.
I'll see you in the next step. Until then,
Bye bye!