welome back. In the previous step we executed the hello worldbeanservice.
We saw that the service was not getting invoked, and we were printing something called observable in the
console.
Now what is this observable thing, and why are we not able to see the service being called on the network?
Typically if I call a http service, it might really take a long time to execute.
Some services might take three to five seconds to execute.
If we do it synchronously, that what would happen because of this and we wait for the response.
And in the meanwhile the entire browser would hang.
That's the reason why we should call all http services asynchronously.
Now observables is one of the best approaches to implementing a synchronous communication.
What it does is, it makes extensive use of observables as the interface for most of the asynchronous operations.
So if you want to make an object's request using the HTTP module, angular internally makes use of this
observable.
The most important thing about observables is this is declarative, in the sense that over here, you can
define what you are allowed to call. We will later look at defining what should happen when I get a response
back, and what should happen when I get an error back.
You can define all that as part of an observable. However, let's look bit later. Over here,
The observable.
is not really executed, as the request is not really executed. We need to do something called
a subscribe.
So basically observable will help us to define: OK, this is the service i would want to call, this is the data
I'm expecting back.
This is the thing which I have to do when there is an error, but it does not really work the service
until somebody subscribes to it.
Let's look at what that means right now.
So let's take this service what I'll do,
I'll do a subscribe.
So what we're doing in here is we are subscribing to this.
Let's say this.
There are things you can do with this object.
I will talk about it a little later.
For now, let's do a subscribe, and do  Get welcome message.
Awesome.
You see it and coming up, it is observable because we had to cancel that log.
We are executing the service.
And it says access to the http request at so and so on is blocked by CORS policy.
No access control allowed, or to get head that is present on the request resources. And you can also see
the details of the HTTPErrorResponse.
The great thing is if you go back in the past now... let's expand this for so that you can clearly see
it.
Let's clear the old stuff out.
Let's click it again.
Now you see that the request is executed but we are not really getting a response back.
It's giving us a response back.
The response is empty there is no data present here.
Why is it happening?
Think about this.
I'm calling from localhost:4200 which you are calling localhost.
:8080 So this is like one Web site we're calling on the web.
So what you're calling a service which is hosted on a different server from your front-end application.
And by default, spring boot prevent these kind of request.
So we need to tell Angular allow requests from a specific you need to tell.
OK hey I know we're secure... you would want me to be safe... but I want to have requests from local host
4200.
How would I do that?
You can do that just by going to our hello world controller and adding a simple annotation @CrossOrigin to
have requests from other domains.
And the best thing is to specify exactly which domains you would want to allow the requests from.
I'd want do requests from only this specific URL.
So only requests from this specific URL will be handled properly.
So I made the change, and because we have to start, the changes automatically pick up. If the change is
not automatically picked up,  you just restart the server.
Now if I go here it's clear that the console.
Let's clear this out as well, and say get welcome message.
And now you'd see that it's printing
But there is no error there.
And if I go to the network tab you would see that the hello world bean message is called, and I'm getting
that response back.
So what is happening now?
As soon as I subscribed to the observable the request is executed.
The interesting thing is if I call subscribe a number of times... I'm now calling it three times... what would
happen?
Let's clear the consoles out
Actually I'm clearing network right now.
I clear the control as well.
If you do get a welcome message what would happen? Now, didn't it work... you'd see that that request will
execute. The the wonderful thing about observables is the fact that just by calling subscribe, you can
execute this same code again and again and again.
So if there is an error out later, this service calls error out and you will want to retry with observables,
It's very very easy.
You just need to call it again.
You just need to subscribe to it.
Again this would retry the entire service call.
Now remove the unnecessary call.
We just want to subscribe to it once.
But what we want to do is we want to pick up data from here.
We want to get the response, and we would want to show a message on the screen.
Let's focus on that the next step . Bye!