Welcome back. In the last step, we saw that when we click the get welcoming message, the hello world bean  service is
called and we saw the response coming back.
However, we were not able to really get the response and print it on the console.
So what we want to do is first get the response, print it on the console, and then make use of it and
show it on the welcome page.
Let's get started with it right now.
The first thing you need to understand is the fact that subscribers send asynchronous call, it means
this one will not return the results, but it will be when a synchronous call in javascript.
What we need to do, is we need to say: what should we do when we get the results back, when we get the
response back.
What should we do?
We should create a function like that, and tie it up to the subscribe.
So what we need to do now, is we need to create a new function.
So I'm going outside to get welcome message.
So let's not really worry about this stuff right now, let's have the subscribing here.
Let's create a new function.
I call this handle successful response.
So what we are saying is if a successful response comes back to this, you have a successful response
response.
And what they do here is for now, let's just do a console log of response. We do a lot more a little
later.
For now, console.log is good enough. and well here, what we need to do is when the successful response
comes back, what does it need to do?
It needs to call the handle successful response. What we are doing in here is called Arrow function.
So what we're defining is, we need to call this.handler successful response, the response which comes
back. You're saying when the subscribe whatever is done, by the observable is successful, get the response
and call this specific method. One other things you would observe.
If I were to log in here.
So let's  do a console.log in here, so that log last line of get welcome message.
Let's see how this works out.
Let's refresh and clear console. Let's call get welcome message.
The thing you'll see is last later welcome message is printed first, and then they say hello world. The
way it works is this is asynchronous call. What happens is all we are saying execute the Hello World
Service,
And whenever response comes back to this. And what we're doing, is just declaring it. We don't really need
a complete execution.
And after that immediately this line is executed, and then the response comes back, maybe after two seconds,
three seconds. What response comes back?
It get printed out to the ground.
So the advantage of this approach is, we're not keeping the thread which is executing this hanging. What
we are saying is just declaring it.
That's the biggest advantage with observables. With observables.
you just declared what needs to be done... and what needs to be done.
If a successful response comes back. If it never comes back and then you'll continue executing the rest
of the code.
And then the response comes back.
It would be appropriately handled, because we have already declared how to handle that.
Now actually instead of doing this,
successfulresponse I could have actually done, it's very easy ... so take console.log.
So instead of this.data, what I could have done this as well.
So let's say I was doing console.log response and I would want to get the message object right.
What we want to do, is we would want to get the welcome message from the response. We would want to pick
up the message. What would happen if I do a respond to the message? It says compilation error.
That response does not exist.
The message does not exist on the response.
Now we know that in the response there is a message.
How do we define the object which is expected back, when I execute a service? We can do that by going to
the welcome data service and over here, I'll create another class defining what kind of response I am
expecting
back. So I'll say export class I'll call this hello world.
And it's create a constructor in here.
Let's define a few public properties, and the structure we expect is the Hello world bean, would contain
a message which is a string.
So what we're doing in here, is we are creating a simple bean defining the structure of the response
that we're expecting.
And the great thing is you can say in the GET, what response structure I'm expecting back? I can say
I am expecting a structure of the kind: hello world bean.
So if you had better generics in Java, this is something very similar to generics in Java. We are saying
we are expecting this kind of response back.
And what I can do in here, is go and see the code would come by and so... what we are now getting is a response
.message.
I'll go back to handle successful response, let's call it the successful response with the response.
And over here, I got compilation error, because this.handles successful response and we're here now.
I can do a response.message.
Let's see what would happen, when I do get ready method.
You'd see that hello world is also being printed up.
That's good.
So what we have done, is we have the response, we are able to get the message from the response, and now
we would want to show it on the welcome component.
So let's create another container, and let's create a quick h2 out here... let's do this.
h2 and /h2 . A customized.
Welcome message over here. What we want over here is the message which comes back from the component.
So what you need to do, is need to first create a member variable.  message ... welcome message.
from service, and I'll say it's a string. What we can do.
now, I would want to populate the welcome message from service. Where can I do that?
I can do that in here. Instead of logging the response and all that stuff, what I'll do is make a message
from service = response.message. compilation error is not there.
So what is happening?
The welcome message is tied up to the response message.
The other thing is I don't really want to show this always.  For that welcome message.
So we see it here now.
I don't really want to show this always.
I want to show it only when welcome message from service has a value. So I put a *ngIf on top of the whole thing.
That's what would happen right now?
Let's say a message, and you can see that I don't need this.
If I can minimize this you can see.
Hello world being printed.
Where is this coming from?
The hello world is coming from this particular thing.
Let's change this to make sure that we are getting it from here.
So I'm saving this.
You can see that.
So it is restarting and picking it up.
So make sure that you restart it and pick it up.
And if you do hello world bean.
Hello world changed is coming up.
That's cool!
And now, get welcome message.
Hello world changed is now being printed.
So what you want to successfully do until now, is we really will call a service in the backend, and we
were able to show the response from it in the friend.
And congratulations and I'll see you in the next step.