Welcome back. In the previous steps, we implemented the Http client, and when we click get a message we get you
a customized welcome message, hello world changed.
That's cool! We're able to get some text back and show it on the front end, and that's wonderful.
But what if something goes wrong?
What if the server is throwing an exception?
What if there's an error when you're calling a specific service?
How do you handle that?
Let's see what would happen. Right now,
There is an error on the server.
I'll comment this out and I'll take a shortcut: throw new
RuntimeException. That's exceptional.
throw new runtime exception and say OK some error has happened.
create a message.
Right some error happened, contact support at so and so OK.
Let's say this was a properly customized error message which is coming up from the server. Let's say this
is the thing which is present right now.
When I say get welcome message now.
What would happen?
It gets an earror response.
Let's load the page again and another click get welcome message.
What would happen?
You'd see that there's an error there.
So it says get 500 error response.
But the user has no signal that some error has happened.
You don't expect error. So go to the console and see the fact that there's an error.
Right?
So you don't want the user to be doing that.
You would want the user to be having a visual representation of what's happening.
You need to tell the user something really going wrong.
How do we do that? well we can do that is by using the Subscribe. Subscribe method the first parameter
is the function to handle successful response.
You can adding another parameter to tell what should happen when there is an error.
at this point. So I can say handle error response, and over here what I can do is I can pass in error.
now what i'll do id: this.handle error response it's not really defined in here.
So let's do that... handle
error response for error.
Let's handle that in here.
So what we need to do.
I'll say this error message from server... is I'm taking a shortcut in here.
The ideal way you do that is probably adding error message at the top.
So you would go to the welcome component.  have another div at the top, which would be shown over here, the
error message is active.
So you would have a *ngIf the error message you might have an added variable in here saying
error message.
And you can populate that for now.
Let's just take a shortcut.
I'll say this.welcome message from service = error.
Let's look at the error object which we printed earlier.
I've not saved this yet, so get would give me an error object.
So this is the response which we get.
If you look at the structure of this, it says error message before doing this, what i'll do is i'll
log it... and console.log()
and console.log() error message, just to confirm that our reading of
The thing is right. Refresh this page.
Now I do get a message?
So what we are saying is this is the response.
This is the response to error, and this is the message that's cool.
So we are able to get the message here.
We just need to fix a little bit of stuff.
So all here should be error.
Message. Let's refresh the page.get welcome mesaage
Some error has happened.
Contact support at so and so.
So now when there's an error we are issuing this text out.
This is the way you can handle it.
What we're doing in here is we are defining a common error response.So we're saying when there's an error.
Do this. What we did in here is, we create data under the parameter with the subscribe, then defining how
to handle the error.
So when there's an error now, what would happen it would call the handle response. Let's comment out
the console.log.
We don't need these anymore.
What is important for us is all the stuff which is presented here.  let's comment  out other things which are present
in here as well, so that we don't really have any logs out there.
What we have is when there's an error in here. Ideally we should act on it in a different block at the
top, but that I would leave it to you as an exercise. For now we have to use the same thing for the success
message and the error message as well.
I'll see you in the next step.
Bye!