Welcome back. In the previous steps we implemented the  get welcome message.
And we implemented the error handling for it.
Let's go back and let's comment  the Exception out, and let's go back to the default stuff that we are
getting the helloworldbean.  Wait for the server to restart . So if you click get
welcome message, you see that it's getting the proper message back. That's good!
So we have the basics of quality http service worked out.  What we do now is we will try and call
the next service.
What we do want to do is, we would want to call this service with the path variable. How do we do that?
It should be a quick exercise to get that done, in this specific step.
So the URL is helloworld/  path variable get that in here quickly.
hello world path variable. it will take in28minutes and then we would get hello world in28minutes as the response.
So this is the URL that we need to call.
So let's pick that up.
We need to first define welcome data service. welcome data.
service... this is where we would go< and here I'd want to use this.
You are going to call it so I'll call this: execute Hello world.
Service with path variable.
And you need a parameter
You need to pass a path name.
So this in28minutes is a parameter it's a path variable  actually.
So how do we pass path variable?
So let's pick this up in this specific thing.
This specific thing is the path variable
It's a variable
But it's not really a constant.
How do we take the name, and put it in here? The way you can do that is by using ticks.
So here what we have is a string (single quote), where you can replace it with a tick.
Here we are putting the tick character in, and when you do  that, you can use something called dollar open brace
and name
So I could have actually done a string append and added name,  but the best practice is to use a tick
inside it.
You can put variables.
So these variable values would get automatically replaced.
So this is so that we would want to call. Let's go back to the welcome component.
Yes I'll copy this get welcome message, and call it get welcome message.
Well what we wanted to do is we want to call this.execute.
hello world service, what is the method that you'd want to call, andcall on the path name as the parameter
of the name as the parameter
And what do you want to do on successful
response, is exactly the same.
So we'd want to get the message and show it.  What I'll do now,  is I'll go to the welcome.component.html
and instead of calling the get welcome message, let's switch to calling get welcome message with.
Parameter. Let's go ahead and call the get welcome message. You would see that get hello world in28minutes
is printed out there. See how easy it is to invoke external services in angular.
Once you have everything worked out. Once you have the framework well-designed, you'd be able to
easily call external services with Angulat. In this step, we created a new method in the welcome data service
which allows us to pass a Parameter, and we executed that from the welcome component.
And we saw that we did not really have to do a lot of work.
I'll see you in the next step. Until then, bye!