Welcome back. Until now, we have created the entire structure of the application. We have created
the welcome page.
We learned how to call a http service in the background.
And now let's start focusing on creating the services.
So until now we have just a list of todos which are being shown, but this list of todos is hardcoded.
What we focus on here on, is to start getting the list of tools from the backend. We would want to be
able to edit to those. We would want to add a new todo, and we would want to be able to delete a
todo. So we would want to create back-end services for each one of those features.
And we would want to be able to invoke them from the front end. The services that we would need.
One I would want to be able to retrieve all the todos for a user.
The second one I would want would be to be able to delete a todo, delete to do of a
users. We would want to be able to edit it  the todo, and we would want to be able to create a new todo which
of course may be used to retrieval all todos for a user.
Typically we would use get or retrieve all the todos for the user, and the way we would design the service
to have URL users /username. For this user, we would want to retrieve all todos.
So we want to do a GET request to users/username. The username would be a path variable, and we would want
to get all the tools for that specific user.
Now how do I delete a specific todo? The way I can do that is by using the delete method.
So I use delete request method, and you'd want to pass in which to do you would want to delete.
So todo_id. Now if you want to edit a todo,
How do we do that?
The way we can do that is by using put method. When you want to edit or update, it it is nothing but an
update and we want to update a resource you'll want to use
Put. The remaining stuff would remain exactly the same as the Delete, to put a specific user.
You would want to update a todo, and the last one is to create a new todo.
Which method would we use to create a new todo? We would be using post method,  and which you want
to post to?
You'd want to post to the todos you are in.
So this would be the resources that we would be creating.
So we could get resource, or delete resource, or put resource, and post resource.
We start with creating this resource to retrieve all the todos for a user, in the next step.
I'll see you in the next step. Until then, Bye!