Welcome back. In the step, I would want to create and save all todo for a user.
Get service. One other things I observed when I went to the package structure, is the way we have organized
our stuff.
It's not really perfect.
What I would want to start with, is I would want to start with leaving these two specific packages.
So I would want to say this bean, I would want to move to a package called Hello world.
.helloworld do control-1 or command-1
And I'll say, move hello world into that package, and I'll also do the similar thing with the hello world
controller.
What I would want to do is move this to
the Helloworld controller.
I want to move to .helloworld package. So I want to move it.  You'd see that everything is very well organized.
So we have all the little pieces in a single package, and we have the last full application in the package.
That's good.
Just make sure that everything is fine, by just running the services again.
So this looks cool.
If you go to the home and just do a get welcome message, and it is looking fine so everything else is fine.
Let's now focus on creating the retrieve all tools for users. is What we do is create a new class.
I call this todo resource, and finish as usual.
We would add at the rest controller annotation, press control space and import the disk controller in
addition.
What do you want to do, as we would want to create a get method to public list of todo's. So you'd want
to return a list of todos, get all Todo's and would want to be able to get them for a specific user.
It would get all todos for a specific user, and we would want to return all those back.
What do you do to start off, is we'll not really talk to a database and all. we'll focus on having a simple
in-memory service. At a later point in time, in due course, we'll convert using JPA and hibernate based API.
So for now let's get started with very very simple things.
Let's focus on one thing at a time.
What I'll do is create a new class, called todo. So control-1  over here, create class todo.
Let's go out and create it in the .todo package and say finish. What I'll do is also more.
The todo service to the .todo package. control-1 move to the .todo package. that's cool, a few compilation errors.
that's fine.
We'll fix them as we go.
Public long id. We want to store an ID should it be public?
Actually it should be private, and I would want to store which user that belongs to, let's do private
String
Username.
What is the description of that specific todo? private String description
You'd want to store the target date, private Date target date and you'd want to store the completion
status is it completed or not? private  boolean isDone. let's import the java.util.date. Be careful,
it should be java .util.date
Let's quickly create the getters and setters, for all the to dos. So i'll generate the getters and setters
and also say select all, and really create getters and setters.
So for all this stuff as well. Let's create a constructor as well.  Teh way i generated the getters ans setters
if you're new to this, is by select all,  generate getters and setters, and yes, there are other methods as
well.
So you can do tostring, generate constructor, and all that stuff.
I also want you to construct, and I do generate constructor using fields.
So alt-shift-s,  and generate constructor,  using fields. So let's generate a constructor.
It's created down here.
I don't really want it down here.
I would want it done here. So quickly it created a bean with a constructor, and also the getters and setters
I'll just a little format it ctrl-shift-f, or command-shift-f,  And let's go to the resource and let's
do an import of java.util...
This is not really compiling because we are not yet returning a list of todos back.
What I would want to do is I would want to create a service.
So I want private todo... start with a hardcoded value,  so we still do hardcored todo service and call this to
do service.
Service does not exist yet, so let's create a control-1 create class todo hardcoded service.
Let's go out and create in the same package, todo package, that's cool. do a finish.
What I would want to do is todo hardcoded service,  I would want to be able to have a static list of those.
So I say private static list of todos... todos =  ... you add a list of todos into the the list, do a
list control-1 and import it in.
You don't really using import it,  right... in here because it's imported from here.
Let's import java.util.List as well. What we'll do is for now,
This would act as our database.
So we would put all the things into this, and create method around it.
Let's initialize the data in this.
So static.
So if you create a static initializer block, and add in todos. add it to create a new todo down here.
So what else do we need to create a new todo? I need a id for the ID, what I'll do is I'll create a quick
private static int idCounter.
= 0.
And each time for every todo. let's do a ++IdCounter,  so IDs would start with 1.
And what's the next parameter? It's  username.
For now it's hardcoded to in28minutes.
The next one is a description.
Let's say we would want to 'learn to dance'.
That's the first one.
Next one is the date, so new Date(),  and for all the todos,  Let's mark them as false to start off. Let's do you a control-1, for java.
util.date,
We're gettign it into here
.date is what we want, and press a semi-colon. Now we have this present,  decrease the font
size a bit so that we can see a little bit more of this stuff . Now that we are typing in a lot of
stuff in here.
I would want to add three
todos: in28mionutes,  learn to dance.
I want to learn about microservices,  I would want to learn about Angular. Is that good?
Let's start with creating a very simple method to return this list of todos.
Right?
So what do we need?
We would want to retrieve all these todos back.
What we'll do is, we'll create a method called Find...list of users,
find all the list of todos that
you are looking for.
Show the list of todos, that I need to say return todos.
Now we have the todos being returned back from here.
One of the things which we are doing in here, is we are editing the spring data JPA, so that
we can easily switch to it later.
For now let's go to the resource, and let's make use of the hardcoded todos. Now, the first thing
which we need to use.
This should be a spring component right?
What we would want,
We don't want to create instances where we want to bring to manage that.
So I would say @component... This is a business service.
So a better thing to do, would be to say this is an @servicecontrol. One important service I'll remove
the component which we imported earlier. And now let's go back to the resource, and now it's the ADD component.
How do I get it in here?
At @Autowire
So we would want to autowire the service
In here, we would want to manage our dependencies, and now back and say Return todo.
service.find()
Now what do you want do? map to this.
We want to map the GET request.
So get mapping, and what is that you are that we would want to map to this?
We already decided that it /users//todos
I'll take that and put it down here.
And instead of user_name,  use username, and this string username is a path variable. We see
we already looked at it. The way we can use this is @PathVariable, control-1,  import path variable.
Now I can import that mapping in. Import it in, and save this. Now, you have a URL.
user/username/ todos.
Now if you go ahead and if you URL: localhost:8080/users.
/in28minutes/todos,
You see these two todos present.
One of the things is right now, as things stand, we are not really using the username variable.
So we choose a username, you put in the service, and all the todos which are present in there. In this
quick step,
We created a service, we wanted to retrieve all the stored todos, and we wanted to connect it to the front
end. So we created a service and we are ready to connect to the back-end.
Let's see how we can do that.
I'll see you in the next step.