Welcome back. In the previous step, we created the todos service.
Now we want to create our mytodo the application to the service from the back end.
How can we do that?
Let's look at that in this specific step.
The first thing we would want to do, is we would want to create a data service. So let's use the command
which we used earlier.
I'll call this ng generate service.
service/data. so we would want to create it in the service/data folder.
And this is what data this has. todo data. todo data.
Let's wait for the service to be created. This is created.
And let's open todo-data.service.ts
So this is the file we just created, and over here, we would want to start creating.
a method. You want to be able to create a method to retrieve the list of todos.
Let's get started with it, by looking at the welcome data service component.
So let's copy the hello world bean service.
what you want to do, is we would want to retrieve all todos.
We have a parameter in here.
What is the parameter?
The username. We would want to be able to retrieve all the things for it, and we would want to first
import http. So let's do added as construct an argument.
So I'll say private http, and would want to say the HttpClient.
So now we have the httpClient.
We would want to use the hello world bean. What we would get is a list of todos. We already have
todo bean.
So I'll say to do we have defined a todo,  in the list-todos component.
So let's use that. If you do a control-,
You'd be able to see the definition of the todo.
So we have a description done, and a target date. cool.
The only thing we don't really have here is a username. but when we are talking about todos on the client
side they are already assigned to a specific user.
So we don't really need the user name in there.
So this is good.
The only change we need to do is they should be an array of todos.
So what we're expecting back is a array of todos, which are coming back.
And now let's change the URL.
What should be the URL?
Localhost:8080. Let's copy the URL from the browser.
This one.
So this should be the URl.
Except that let's use tick and tick over here.
Over here.
And now I can replace this with a variable name. But it should not be in28minutes but it should be username
cool.
Now we have to retrieve all this data.
service method ready. We would want to be able use todo data  service, where? In the list-todos component
right!
We have a hard coded list of todos in here, which are being used.
So what I'll do is I'll comment all these steps and say control-. or command-/,  and comment all this
stuff and we'll have a todos.
This is nothing but three todos.
So I'll say :todos, so we don't really have todos initialized.
What I would want to do is in the end, we only need what we want to do, is we don't initialized the todo
, as we would want to be able to call the todo data
Service. Before doing that, we should be able to use the todo data service, because todo data service
is defined as @injectable. To be able to use dependency injection.
So what I'll do is over here, is a private service.
This is what you'd want to use todo data service, and call this todo service. Just to be clear,
What you want to do is,  this.todoservice.retrieveAllTodos(),  and to this I would need
to pass in a username.
How can I get the username?
One of the ways is to quickly hard code it. Will this work?
No! The reason why this would not work is because the retrieve all todos
Actually returns
What did ... what does it return?
It returns an observable.
And what we would need to do is, we need to do a subscriber on it.
So what we need to do is subscribe, and we need to define what should happen when you get a successful
respond. So when I get a successful response. what should we do?
Let's define the method in here.
What we want to do when we get a successful response is: this.todos lose =
What I'll also do is console.log() a response, so that we can see what's coming back in response.So
what we are doing is we are calling the retrieveAllTodos,  All the hardcoded in28minutes, and we are subscribing
to that response, and we get the response back.
What we want to do, is we want to log the response and assign it to the todos. Go to the todos application
click todos,
Whoops.
Nothing is visible. Let's expand and see what the error is.
What do you think the error is?
As usual, CORS policy.
Let's go to the hello world control-F, ,  and take this cross-origin,  and put it in to resource as well.
Let's refresh now.
You see that all this stuff which we're interested in is coming up.
Let's close this, and you'll see that we have the list of  todos that we are having in a database that's
coming up.
Not really the database, the in-memory database.
If you can call it that way.
All those things are coming up. So we have home, and we have a get welcome message, service which is getting called
And when we click todos,  we are calling a service, and we are getting data back, and we are showing it
down to the user.
So we are making progress.
In terms of actually connecting our front-end to the back end, there are a lot of things that we would
still need to improve.
But we are making progress towards our goal of having the todo application really.
I'll see you in the next step, and until then,  bye-bye.