Welcome back! In the step, you'll want to help you get quickly started this course.
The first thing I would want to do, is to congratulate you on making a great decision in choosing this
course.
Now, let's get down to getting started with the course.
The first thing you would need to do, is to bookmark the GitHub repository of this course.
You'll find a link to it in the resources section of the video you are watching.
You just have to hover over to the left top corner of your screen, and you should see resources, and a
link to the repository.
Just click it, and launch the GitHub repository, and bookmark the URL. The repository contains links
to all the installation we use,
Step-by-step details of the code and the source code.
Also present is backup of all the code at various points.
For example, this is the last backup.
This is the final backup of the code in this specific course. yYou'd see that the backup is present as
a single file, so that if you face a problem you can use this as a reference.
You can look at how it is done here, and check how you are approaching it.
The first two sections of this course would extensively focus on Angular. The tools you would need for
that section is NPM, and Visual Studio Code.
We can install Java and Eclipse a little later.
For now you can launch this playlist which would help us to install NodeJS, which is NPM, and Visual Studio
Code.
This list contains three steps: Installing nodejs, and npm,  a quick introduction to NPM, and installing
Visual Studio Code.
I would recommend to pause the video in here, and continue with the installation of nodejs and Visual
Studio Code.
If you have successfully installed nodejs and Visual Studio Code,  you are now all set to rock the
Angular world.
If you are a Java developer, the first few steps can be overwhelming.
You will be using a new language. More than javascript and typescript, you will be using a new IDE,  Visual
Studio Code. You'll be using a new framework: Angular, with a new tool: Angular CLI,  which is used to create
angular projects.
The first seven steps contain a little bit of theory, to introduce you to the various part of developing
modern javascript applications.
Once you get to the second section of the course, you'll be spending 95 percent of the time getting your
hands dirty.
The recommended approach to follow in the course, is to take steps one at a time.
Do them in the order which is present in here.
If you are in a hurry to get your hands dirty and write a lot of code, then you can skip step 6 and
Step 7, and come back to them a little later. We'll talk about all the remaining sections of this course
when we get to them.
Let's get started with understanding the application.
architecture, in the next step.