Welcome back.
I'm excited to help you learn full stack application development with Angular and Spring Boot, and I'm
sure you are as excited as I am. In this step,
let's discuss the high level architecture of the application,
we are going to build in this specific course.
Let's start with understanding the basic functionality of the application that we are going to build.
We're going to build a TODO management application.
Everyone has things you would want to do.
, you'd want to learn.
You can manage them in this specific TODO management application.
You can add TODO, delete TODO, and update TODO.
Other than that you, also have authentication and authorization features, typically login and logout
capabilities.
Let's now shift our attention towards the high level architecture of this application.
What we are going to develop is a full stack application.
When we talk about a full stack application, we are talking about a front end application, which is talking
to a backend API or a web service. We'll be using Angular to build the front-end application. Angular is
One of the most popular frameworks to build front-ends. Angular has a variety of features like components,
modules, forms, HTTP communication to talk with the web services.
It makes it easy to develop front-end applications, and gives the users a language called Typescript.
If you're new to typescript, then typescript is nothing but modern Javascript +  typing
We'll discuss a little bit more about typescript in a subsequent video. For now, it's sufficient to understand
that the front-end application will be developed using the Angular framework, which would be based on a
language called typescript. To build a RESTful API or the RESTful services in the back-end,
we would be using the Spring SpringBoot framework.
We would be using Java as the language. SpringBoot is the number one Java framework to build RESTful
APIs and microservices. We will create multiple RESTful services for authentication, as well as
to do management. As far as authentication is concerned, we will start with basic authentication and
also discuss about how to use JWTs,  or JSON Web Tokens, for authentication.
We will be using the spring security framework to build authentication around this API. Before we move
on to the next step,
let's discuss an important question.
We're talking about full stack application.
Why should you really build a full stack application?
Why should you create a separate back-end, and a separate front-end?
And there is a lot of complexity associated with building separate back-end.
For instance, you need to understand multiple languages.
You need to understand multiple frameworks, like SpringBoot and Angular.
Why should you do that?
The most important reason is to create a flexible architecture, which can be extended to meet the future
needs.
Let's imagine that you would want to develop a native mobile application in future, that you would want
to develop an iPhone app, or you would want to develop an Android application.
Maybe you would want to connect with the Internet of Things devices. In such kind of situations,
You can completely reuse the backend API that is being exposed. The full-stack application with a separate
backend API or the RESTful API, and a front-end will give you more options to extend your architecture
and create applications for different devices.
In this quick video, we looked at the architecture of the application that we are going to create, create
an angular application, talking to a RESTful API built on top of SpringBoot.
We discussed why we build full stack applications.
I'll see you in the next video. Until then, Bye-bye!