Welcome back! When we discussed the architecture of the application that we are going to build,
we said we would develop the front-end
as an Angular application, using typescript as the language. We discussed the fact that typescript is
nothing more than Javascript + types.
Now in this video,
Let's understand what is more than javascript,  what is typescript.
If you built web applications a few years back, you would have written a lot of javascript.
You would have played with the DOM,  which is the Document Object Model.
I'm sure the javascript you wrote would not have looked something like this.
A number of developers are surprised with the evolution of javascript in the last few years.
Modern Javascript support features like classes,
You even have annotations. However these annotations in Javascript are called decorators.
You can import classes from modules. So modern Javascript has all the features that are typically present
in object oriented programming languages like Java.
Let's look at a quick history of the versions of javascript.
You can see that the javascript versions are ES3, ES5, ES6, ES7 and ES8.
What does ES stand for? ES stands for ECMAScript.
ECMAScript is nothing but a standard.
And javascript is the implementation of that standard.
It's like the interface and the class. A class is an implementation of the interface. Similar to that
what is specified in ECMAScript is implemented by Javascript. Javascript's
version are specified as ES3, ES5,  6, 7 and 8.
You can see that there is a huge time gap between ES3 and ES5, as well as ES5 and ES6. All the
versions which are after ES6.
So ES 6 and the versions after that are what I would typically call as Modern Javascript, because these
are the versions which support classes and modules, and they help you to write modularized, well-organized Javascript
code. Of late,
The year in which ECMAScript standard has been released is also being used to represent the version.
So E6 was released in 2015, so this is also called ES2015. ES2016 is nothing but ES7.
ES2017 is nothing but ES8.
Now what is typescript?
Why do we need it?
Typescript is nothing but Javascript +
typing... what does that mean?
Thing is Javascript is a loosely type language.
When you declare a variable you cannot not really define the type of the variable.
Ok here we are saying there value... we are saying value is a variable.
We can not say value is an integer variable.
But what happens because of this is, you can assign a number 5, or you can assign a string.
Or you can even assign an object.
This is a little different from a strongly typed language like Java.
In Java you can say int value;,  which means value is an  integer variable, and you can only have integer numbers in
value.
If you say value = "Five", it gives you a compilation error.  The reason why typing is important, is because it
helps us to write maintainable code.
Errors will be caught directly at compile time.
When you write code with typescript it would look something like this.
Over here, we are saying value is a number, and when we assign a numeric value to value,
This is fine.
However if you assign a text value,
This would give you a compilation error.
The syntax is a little different, but essentially it exactly represents the same. Typescript also has features
like: you can define types on method parameters.
So over here in this method, this parameter number1 I'm saying is a number,
This number2 is a number.
You can also define the return type of a method. Over here, before the colon and declared the return type.
The other thing typescript adds, is
the concept of interface, and having the class implement the interfaces. In this course, we will use
learn-as-we-go-approach to learn more on javascript and typescript.
We don't need features like a class, a constructor, a decorator, or an import.
We will take a pause and discuss it to ensure that you have a good understanding before we use the feature.
In this quick video, we discussed the fact that Javascript has evolved a lot in the last few years
Javascript helps us to write maintainable javascript code using classes, modules, imports, decorators
and a wide variety of other features. Typescript helps us write even safer code than javascript by
adding type-safety, with which you can identify errors at compile-time itself.
This video was just to give you a quick overview around typescript and modern javascript.
We will look at a lot of hands-on examples as we go on forward with this course.
I'll see you in the next step.