Welcome back. In this step, let's focus on installing Angular CLI.
If you google for Angular CLI, the first result would be cli.angular.io.
Once you get to that web page, you would see that Angular CLI is a command line interface for Agular.
If there was ever an understatement, then this is the one!
Angular CLI
not only helps you create new Angular applications, but also it helps you to generate a lot of code while
we are developing the angular application.
It helps us to run our application locally, and also run our unit tests.
integration tests, run our code quality checks and things like that.
Installing Angular CLI is very very easy.
The first step is to launch up your terminal or command prompt.
So I'm on Mac.
I'm launching up my terminal and you can see that the terminal has launched up.
If you're on Windows make sure that you are launching up your command prompt.
All that you need to do is to click the Start button.
Typing cmd, the CMT command prompt would come up and make sure that you are bringing it up as an administrator.
So I click on it and make sure that you are running it as an administrator.
You would have your terminal command prompt launched up.
So let's go ahead and check our Node version which is installed. The way
you can check your node version is node -v.  And we make sure that you at least have v 8. If you want
you can go and check the npm version as well. So the npm version that we have here is 6.4, and any version which
is better than 6 should be fine. If you don't have these options right.
then I would recommend to go and check the installation video for node version again, and make sure that
you have the right version right now.
We are all set to start installing angular CLI,  and Angular CLI is present as an npm module.
So all that you need to do, is do npm install -g @angular/cli
I would want to get the latest version of Angular that 7.
So I'll add at 7..
So the command is very simple.
npm install -g @angular@cli@7.0.3
If you have problems typing in you can also copy it from here, and append at 7.0.3 and I would press enter.
Now what would happen is to download the Angular CLI,
One of the important things if you're a Java developer, you can kind of think of NPM as Maven. Like
Maven download the dependencies the plugins for you.
So Angular CLIis almost like a maven plugin, and we are using NPM to download it for us.
This download might take a little while.
If you are on a slow network or if you are doing this for the first time and the install.
I got an error.
It is missing right.
Access to.
So if you got this error if you got the same error that I got then it means you don't have admin permissions
so if you're on Windows you can have admin permissions when you run a command prompt, is by making sure
that when you're launching up the command prompt, you are launching it as: click and on as-administrator
so this will ensure that you have admin rights when you are launching at the command prompt. On Mac or
on Linux,  you can assign admin permissions is by using sudo.
So I just need to type in sudo before the command.
I'm saying sudo space and npm space install and the exec and as it goes.
So no it would ask me for the administrator password to go out and interview a password.
If you have any I wanted my password and now you see that it would start doing the same process again.
So this is very important when we installed node module.
Make sure that you have admin rights. Now you can see that there is a local module installed, so it saves
+ Angular/cli@7.0.3
Because I did this on my machine earlier, it happened very fast down here.
It may be a couple of minutes on a slow network.
When the installation of Angular CLI is complete, we can go out and test it.
The way you can check the version of the Angular CLI is by saying ng version.
ng version this should give you the version of Angular CLI that is installed.
So here I can see that I'm using Angular CLI version 7.0.3 .
You can also see that Node version,  and also you can see the versions of a few other packages which Angular
CLI makes use of. The most important thing for us is that any version which is greater than 7
is good enough.  In this Quick step, we installed Angular CLI which should be used to generate our first angular
application.
I'll see you in the next step.
Until then, bye-bye!