In the previous step, we have installed Angular CLI.
Let's create our first Angular application using Angular CLI, in this specific step.
Before we get started with creating an Angular App,  let's learn a little bit more about ng,  the Angular
CLI.
So ng help is what you need to type to get help on the Angular client.
You can see all the different commands which are present in here.
We've were already used ng version.
ng version gives you what version of AngularCLI do you have
So ng space version would give you the version of the Angular CLI which is installed.
Let's go ahead and try and help again.
You can see that there are a wide variety of commands available.
ng new which is present over here is used to create an angular App.
So when you want to create a new Angular project, you can say ng new.
The other useful command is ng generate. When we talk about angular applications,
They are built using modules, components,  reuse the initial code for those modules and components can
be generated by using the command
ng generate. The other commands which are available are: to build your code,  to run the code quality checks which
is called in,  to run the application, to run your unit tests, as well as your end-to-end tests.
One of my favorite commands which is present in here is called ng serve. If I use the command and
ng serve... then I suppose I make a code change.
The change would be automatically picked up by the application.
OK.
Enough Theory Now.
Let's get to the practical stuff. Before we start creating an Angular app,
You need to make a first decision, right, where you want to create it.
So you need the cd down to the folder where you would want to create the specific project .I'd want to
create the project in the directory that I'm showing on the screen right now.
The most important thing is, just have a sub-folder called  front-end, so that all the front-end code goes in there.
So I'm cd-ing to that folder.
And here is where you would want to create our Angular project.
The way would create an Angular project is by ng new, and the name of the project.
So use the command ng new  that we would want to create. If you press
enter right now.
And It would ask you a few questions.
The first thing is would you like to have angular routing?
Yes. I would have multiple screens, and I would want to have a screen fill between them.
So I would add Angular routing.
We'll talk about Angular routing in detail, a little later.
I'll say yes.
The question it's asking me is, which style sheet format would you like to use.
The default is the SASS.
You can use arrow buttons to scroll down and scroll up.
I would want to stick with the SASS, to keep things simple.
You can see that it started creating your angular application.
There might be a few warnings.
You can ignore them.
The project is generated and it's actually now trying to build the project.
If this is the first time you're building an Angular project on your machine, it might take a long while,
a few minutes in certain circumstances.
You can see that the installation is going on.
And finally you'll see the success message!
Now, if I want to list the contents of the directories either ls, or the dir, you would see that there's
a folder called "todo" which is created in here.
Let cd into todo/,  and type in ls or dir.
So if you're on Windows the command is dir, instead ls.
What you would see, is a project is created inside the folder todo.
And there are a wide variety of files which are present in here.
Make sure that you are inside the todo folder, and now you can start executing the command to build
and run the application. So we would be using the command  ng  serve.
So type in ng  serve, and press , and you can see that it's listening on local host at 4200,
And it's actually building the modules right now.
So we need to wait until this is hundred percent... okay! Now it's 100%,  and it doesn't and it just compile successfully
and it's opening up in the browser at this specific location so the recommended browser that we would
be using through this course is Google Chrome.
So make sure that you're using Chrome as well. In Chrome.
Go out and type in localhost:4200, and just press .
COOL!! You see page come up... it says Welcome to todo!
And you would see a few links to the angler blog: tutorials and CLI documentation.
If you had an error when you were running this command.
Make sure that you did a CD into the todo folder.
So make sure that you are inside the todo folder before running the command ng.
So that's a common mistake a lot of new comers do in this step.
We were able to quickly generate it on the app and we were able to run it.
Our real journey starts from the next step.
We would start understanding what's happening in the background as well, as you would start creating our
own Angular app.
I'm excited to bring all this to you ,and I'll see you in the next video.